<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecSimpL1" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicTerminology" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Simplified natural language — Part 1: Basic concepts and general principles</title><abbr>SimpL-1</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Simplified natural languages for effective cross-language, cross-domain and cross-system applications</scope><keyword>simplified languages</keyword><keyword>cross-language</keyword><keyword>cross-domain</keyword><keyword>unambiguous language</keyword><info type="description"><p>Language resource management - Simplified natural language — Part 1: Basic concepts and general principles 
            (abbreviated as SimpL-1) is developed since 2009 by the ISO and currently is at the Working Draft stage (ISO/AWI 24620-1).</p><p>It is a common knowledge that natural language is very versatile and offers a wide range of drives speech varieties, 
            styles, grammatical constructions etc. Sometimes it is difficult for experts to understand a text in their own scientific 
            field, and the more for just ordinary readers. The problems increase, whether the text should be understood by non-native 
            speakers or be translated by an expert in this field.</p><p>The goal of the standard is to create a specification, which describes a set of writing rules and a dictionary of agreed 
            words with their definition. It provides a clear and unambiguous language (for example Simplified English for English), 
            which is comprehensible to (all) native and non-native speakers.</p><p>The key tasks of basic concepts and general principles for simplified natural languages are:</p><ul><li>"Reducing ambiguity;</li><li> Speeding up reading;</li><li>Improving comprehension for people whose first language is not the language of the document at hand;</li><li> Improving comprehension for people with different domain or application background;</li><li>Human translation and localization to become easier, faster and more cost effective;</li><li> Computer-assisted translation and machine translation;</li><li>Re-usability of language resources in larger application scenarios, like Semantic Web or decision-support systems.” 
            (ISO/PWI 24620-1)</li></ul><p>Furthermore, this specification builds a systematic approach that can make cross-language and cross-domain applications of 
           simplified natural languages more effective.</p><p> Creating understandable texts is very challenging, especially in an internationally collaborated project where the project
            partners are of different backgrounds and from different institutions and countries. The effective and 
            coherent use of simplified natural language allows a better compatibility between several applications and resources.</p><p>A kind of Simplified English exists and was originally developed as a “controlled language” for aerospace 
            industry maintenance manuals. The purpose of this standard is to develop simplified natural language in many languages and for various  
            application fields.</p></info><version id="SpecSimpl1-AWI" status="New Work Item Proposal"><titleStmt>
            <!-- <title>Language resource management - Simplified natural language — Part 1: Basic concepts and general principles</title>--><respStmt id="WBHCoF"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG5">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 5<!-- liaision with ISO/TC 37/SC 1/WG 4 (Socio-terminology)--></name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO/AWI 24620-1</versionNumber><date>2010-10-21</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address></version></spec>