<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecLaf" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicGenAnn" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://localhost:8080/exist/apps/clarin/xsd/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Linguistic annotation framework</title><abbr>LAF</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Corpus annotation</scope><info type="description"><p>Since June 2012 LAF (stands for Linguistic Annotation Framework) has been accepted and ranked as ISO 24612:2012 
            standard for providing architecture for creation, multiple-annotation and management of linguistic resources.</p><p>The framework specifies the glossary, the common mechanisms of the abstract data model and methods for 
            descriptions of multiple linguistic data annotations. LAF defines the mechanisms for implementing 
            constraints in an annotation scheme, but it does not have specific constraints for individual annotation 
            schemes. </p><p>Although the data model and document form of LAF are distinct, they can be mapped to any
            other annotation scheme. LAF specifies the pivot format, which 
            allows mapping from an annotation scheme into another annotation scheme.
            Therefore, the user can choose his own annotation form, given that it can be
            transferred into the pivot format, called GrAF (Graph Annotation Format).</p><p>In the future, LAF should be able to represent mostly the reality of
            linguistic information of language resources for different media types. The primary data 
            and the annotation documents will be separated.</p></info><version id="SpecLaf-IS" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><respStmt id="sUNDzf"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG1">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 1</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 24612:2012</versionNumber><date>2012-06-15</date><features><fs><f name="metaLanguage"><symbol value="XML"/></f><f name="grammarClass"><symbol value="LTG"/></f><f name="formalModel"><symbol value="Graph"/></f><f name="notation"><symbol value="Standt off"/></f><f name="multipleHierarchies"><fs><f name="support"><binary value="yes"/></f><f name="item"><vColl><string>standoff annotation</string></vColl></f></fs></f></fs></features><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecXces" type="isPartOf"><info><p>Primary document header is based on the XCES.</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecXML" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>LAF's pivot format GrAF is an application of XML.</p></info></relation>
    <!-- <relation target="graf" type="isApplicationOf">
     <p>GrAF is an extension of the LAF, which allows to represent the stand-off annotations of the LAF data model in one Graph.</p>                
        </relation> --></version></spec>