<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecCes" standardSettingBody="SBEAGLES" topic="TopicGenAnn" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Corpus Encoding Standard</title><abbr>CES</abbr></titleStmt><scope>corpus annotation</scope><keyword>corpus</keyword><keyword>CES</keyword><keyword>corpus encoding</keyword><keyword>linguistic annotation</keyword><info type="description"><p>CES is an encoding standard for corpus annotation. It was developed within the framework of the EAGLES (Expert 
            Advisory Group on Language Engineering Standards) project. The aim of the CES is to provide a unitary coding standard for 
            linguistic corpus annotation. The CES can be used to encode corpora as resources for natural language processing.</p><p>SGML (ISO 8879:1986 Standard Generalized Markup Language) was the foundation
			of the CES. Beside the SGML, TEI (Text Encoding Initiative) Guidelines were taken into account for
			the development of the CES. Like the TEI, the CES standardizes the document structure (e.g.
			title, caption, break) or document info (metadata). In addition to that, the CES standardizes the linguistic
			annotation of a text (e.g. morpho-syntactic tagging, parallel text alignment, prosody,
			phonetic transcription, etc.). TEI P3 and the CES are compatible to each other, so they can be used 
			side by side. As an XML-based version of the CES, XCES (Corpus Encoding Standard for XML) has also been developed .</p><p>The CES can be applied in monolingual, multi-lingual and parallel corpora.</p></info><version id="SpecCes4-1" status="final"><titleStmt><respStmt id="IKdc87"><resp>Author</resp><name type="person">Nancy Ide</name><name type="person">Greg Priest-Dorman</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">4.1</versionNumber><date>1996-10-14</date><features><fs><f name="metaLanguage"><symbol value="SGML"/></f><f name="constraintLanguage"><symbol value="DTD"/></f><f name="grammarClass"><symbol value="LTG"/></f><f name="formalModel"><symbol value="Tree"/></f><f name="notation"><symbol value="Standoff"/></f><f name="multipleHierarchies"><fs><f name="support"><binary value="yes"/></f><f name="item"><vColl><string>standoff annotation</string></vColl></f></fs></f></fs></features><address type="URL">http://www.cs.vassar.edu/CES/</address><relation target="SpecTeiP3" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>CES is an application of the SGML-based TEI P3 using the TEI modification layer.</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecXces" type="isVersionOf"><info><p>CES is the SGML ancestor of the XML-based XCES.</p></info></relation></version><asset><a href="../doc/test.txt">CES_Specification.pdf</a></asset></spec>