<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecRNG" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicConstraintLanguage" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>REgular LAnguage for XML Next Generation</title><abbr>RELAX NG</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Regular Grammar-based constraint language for defining document grammars for XML markup languages.</scope><info type="description"><p>RELAX NG stands for Regular Language Description for XML New Generation. It is a schema language for structure definition of XML documents,
            which is based originally on TREX (Tree Regular Expressions for XML) and RELAX Core.</p><p> The RELAX NG was developed by a committee specification of the OASIS RELAX NG technical committee and is ranked as international standard 
            ISO/IEC 19757-2 within Document Schema Definition Languages (DSDL).</p><p>Like the XML Schema (Recommendation of W3C), the RELAX NG is a schema validation language, which uses XML syntax, supports namespaces and data typing. 
            However, the purpose of the RELAX NG was to develop an alternative to the XML Schema, which is by far not so complex and is easy to learn and to use.</p><p>Compared to the XML Schema, the RELAX NG is a valid XML and grammar-based schema language for description of class in XML documents, 
            but is not so expansive. Particularly, it focuses on description and validation of the structure in XML document.</p><p>The main differences between the two technologies is the description of elements. The XML schema contains almost twice as many 
            elements as the RELAX NG schema and describes the elements in details, whereas the RelaxNG simplifies them and creates more readable definitions.</p><p> Other differences between the RELAX NG and the XML Schema are:</p><ul><li>The RELAX NG affords ambiguity in content models and mixed content.</li><li>In the RELAX NG, elements and attributes are treated in a similar manner.</li><li>The RELAX NG can standardize a set of datatypes only and does not have deference between global or local elements. However, 
                it allows the definition and referencing of implicit containers, what is sufficient to handle a huge range of applications.</li><li>Type library is very limited and have only two datatypes (string and token), but it can be expanded with external libraries of 
                datatypes for example from XML Schema.</li></ul></info><version id="SpecRelaxingOasis" status="OASIS Standard"><titleStmt><title>RELAX NG Specification</title><abbr internal="yes">RELAX NG-2001</abbr><respStmt id="VVKozV"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org">OASIS RELAX NG TC</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="minor">Committee Specification</versionNumber><date>2001-12-03</date><address type="URL">https://www.oasis-open.org/committees/tc_home.php?wg_abbrev=relax-ng</address></version><version id="SpecRelaxingISO" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><title>Information technology — Document Schema Definition Language (DSDL) – Part 2: Regular-grammar-based validation</title><abbr internal="yes">RELAX NG-ISO</abbr><respStmt id="EShfHm"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-JTC1-SC34-WG1">ISO/JTC 1/SC 34/WG 1</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="minor">ISO/IEC 19757-2:2008</versionNumber><date>2008-12-10</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address></version></spec>