<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecSynAF" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicSynAnn" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Syntactic annotation framework</title><abbr>SynAF</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Syntactic corpus annotation</scope><info type="description"><p>The abbreviation SynAF stands for Syntactic Annotation Framework. It was developed within
			the eContent LIRICS project and then it has been taken over and developed further by Technical
			Committee ISO/TC 37 (Terminology and Other Language Resources), Subcommittee SC 4 (Language
			Resource Management). Since 2010, SynAF has been accepted and ranked as ISO 24615:2010
			standard.</p><p>The SynAF is complementary and closely based on ISO 24611 (MAF, morpho-syntactic annotation
			framework). Nevertheless, in contrast to MAF, which describes such features as part of speech, morphological
			and grammatical features, SynAf describes a word overall analysis. This specifies the
			syntactic relations existing between single words and how words are arranged and connected to
			build phrases and sentences.</p><p>The objectives of SynAF are to describe a meta-model for representing the syntactic
			annotation of textual documents and to offer a set of data categories, as basis for
			unitary syntactic annotation of language resources or language processing components.</p><p>With SynAF the two main kinds of syntactic annotation can be represented: the constituent and
			dependency structures. SynAF allows to handle syntactic ambiguities and to differentiate
			between shallow and deep annotations.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct id="bib2SY" type="conferencePaper"><analytic><title>SynAF: Towards a Standard for Syntactic Annotation</title><author><forename>Thierry</forename><surname>Declerck</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>Proceedings of LREC</title><imprint><pubPlace>Genoa, Italy</pubPlace><date>2006</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><version id="SpecSynAF-IS" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><respStmt id="TV90TL"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG6">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 6</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 24615:2010</versionNumber><date>2010-10-19</date><features><fs><f name="formalModel"><symbol value="Graph"/></f><f name="notation"><symbol value="Standoff"/></f><f name="multipleHierarchies"><fs><f name="support"><binary value="yes"/></f><f name="item"><vColl><string>standoff annotation</string></vColl></f></fs></f></fs></features><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecDcr" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>The syntactic tag sets are based on data categories from the DCR (ISO 12620 Data Category Registry)</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecMaf-IS" type="isUsedBy"><info><p>The SynAF relies complementary and closely on ISO 24611 (MAF, morpho-syntactic annotation framework).</p></info></relation></version></spec>