<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecTei" standardSettingBody="SBTEIC" topic="TopicGenAnn TopicMarkupLanguage" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Guidelines for Electronic Text Encoding and Interchange</title><abbr>TEI Guidelines</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Texts of the Digital Humanities</scope><info type="description"><p>The TEI Guidelines have been developed and are maintained by the Text Encoding Initiative
            Consortium (TEI) and are designed for people working with any kind of textual resource
            in digital form.</p><p>The guidelines present recommendations of suitable ways of representing the features of textual
            resources, which need to be identified explicitly in order to facilitate processing by
            computer programs. In particular, they specify a set of markers (or tags) which can be
            inserted in the electronic representation of the text, to mark the text
            structure and other features of interest. Many computer programs depend on the
            presence of such explicit markers for their functionality. Without the markers, a
            digitized text appears to be nothing but a sequence of undifferentiated bits. 
            
            The success of the World Wide Web, for example, is partly because of its use of such
            markup to indicate features, such as headings and lists on individual pages, and to
            indicate links between pages. The process of inserting such explicit markers for
            implicit textual features is often called ‘markup’, or equivalently within this work
            ‘encoding’; the term ‘tagging’ is also used informally. We use the term encoding scheme
            or markup language to denote the complete set of rules associated with the use of markup
            in a given context. Besides, we use the term markup vocabulary for the specific set of markers or
            named distinctions employed by a given encoding scheme. Thus, this work describes both 
            the TEI encoding scheme, and documents the TEI markup vocabulary.</p><p>The TEI encoding scheme is of particular usefulness in facilitating the loss-free
            interchange of data amongst individuals and research groups using different programs,
            computer systems, or application software. Since they contain an inventory of the
            features most often deployed for computer-based text processing, the guidelines are also
            useful as a starting point for those designing new systems and creating new materials,
            even where interchange of information is not a primary objective.</p></info><version id="SpecTeiP3" status="final"><titleStmt><respStmt id="eBBHV3"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="person">C. M. Sperberg-McQueen</name><name type="person">Lou Burnard</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">P3</versionNumber><date>1994-05-16</date><features><fs><f name="metaLanguage"><symbol value="SGML"/></f><f name="constraintLanguage"><symbol value="DTD"/></f><f name="grammarClass"><symbol value="LTG"/></f><f name="formalModel"><symbol value="Tree"/></f><f name="notation"><symbol value="Inline"/></f><f name="multipleHierarchies"><vColl><string>milestones</string><string>fragments</string><string>feature structures</string></vColl></f></fs></features><address type="URL">http://www.tei-c.org/Vault/GL/P3/index.htm</address><relation target="SpecSGML" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>TEI P3 is an application of the Standard Generalized Markup Language (SGML).</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecCes" type="isSuperclassOf"><info><p>TEI P3 is the superclass of CES. CES is a modification of a part of the TEI P3's DTD.</p></info></relation></version><version id="SpecTeiP4" status="final"><titleStmt><respStmt id="VaHeZs"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="person">C. M. Sperberg-McQueen</name><name type="person">Lou Burnard</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">P4</versionNumber><date>2002-03-01</date><features><fs><f name="metaLanguage"><symbol value="XML"/></f><f name="constraintLanguage"><symbol value="DTD"/></f><f name="grammarClass"><symbol value="LTG"/></f><f name="formalModel"><symbol value="Tree"/></f><f name="notation"><symbol value="Inline"/></f><f name="multipleHierarchies"><vColl><string>milestones</string><string>fragments</string><string>feature structures</string></vColl></f></fs></features><address type="URL">http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p4-doc/html/</address><relation target="SpecXML" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>TEI P4 is an application of the Extensible Markup Language (XML). It uses the XML syntax for instances and XML DTD as document grammar formalism.</p></info></relation></version><version id="SpecTeiP5" status="final"><titleStmt><respStmt id="N2lu7f"><resp>Editor</resp><name>Lou Burnard</name><name>Syd Bauman</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">P5</versionNumber><versionNumber type="minor">1.9.1</versionNumber><date>2011-03-05</date><features><fs><f name="metaLanguage"><symbol value="XML"/></f><f name="constraintLanguage"><symbol value="RELAX NG"/></f><f name="grammarClass"><symbol value="STG"/></f><f name="formalModel"><symbol value="Tree"/></f><f name="notation"><symbol value="Standoff"/></f><f name="multipleHierarchies"><vColl><string>milestones</string><string>fragments</string><string>standoff annotation</string><string>feature structures</string></vColl></f></fs></features><address type="URL">http://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html</address><relation target="SpecXML" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>TEI P5 is an application of the Extensible Markup Language (XML). It uses the XML syntax for instances.</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecRNG" type="isApplicationOf"><info><p>TEI P5 uses RELAX NG as document grammar formalism.</p></info></relation></version></spec>