<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecThesauri" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicThesaurus TopicControlledVocabulary" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Information and documentation — Thesauri and interoperability with other vocabularies</title><abbr>Thesauri and interoperability with other vocabularies</abbr></titleStmt><scope>International standards for building, management and using of thesauri</scope><keyword>Thesaurus</keyword><keyword>Vocabulary</keyword><keyword>Information retrieval</keyword><keyword>Data representation</keyword><info type="description"><p>The multi part standard ISO 25964 is the revision and substitution of the two existing international standards ISO 2788:1986 and 
            ISO 5964:1985, because the technology, the scale of application, the function and the new knowledge of using such controlled 
            vocabularies in digital world and on the web have changed significantly during the last years.</p><p>The main goal of the standard is to describe the basic principles of building, management and using of thesauri and it details 
             the functions of a controlled vocabulary.</p></info>
    <!--    <relation target="SpecDC" type=""></relation>
    XML Schema uses  Dublin Core elements  --><part id="SpecThesauri-Part1"><version id="SpecThesauri-1" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><title>Information and documentation — Thesauri and interoperability with other vocabularies — Part 1: Thesauri for information retrieval</title><respStmt id="pThes1"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC46-SC9-WG8">ISO/TC 46/SC 9/WG 8</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 25964-1:2011</versionNumber><date>2011-08-08</date><info type="description"><p>"The first Part of the ISO 25964 standard is based on two standards: ISO 2788 (Guidelines for the establishment and 
                    development of monolingual thesauri), ISO 5964 (Guidelines for the establishment and development of multilingual thesauri)
                    and BS 8723 (Structured Vocabularies for Information Retrieval).</p><p>The goal of the standard is to provide the guidelines for the development and maintenance of structured vocabularies 
                    dedicated to information retrieval applications. It can be applied in monolingual and multilingual thesauri as well. 
                    Indexing is covered by using ISO 999:1996 (Information and documentation -- Guidelines for the content, organization 
                    and presentation of indexes).</p><p>The standard is a recommendations management or development of thesaurus only, but not for databases or software
                    used directly in search or indexing applications.  </p></info><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecSV1-BSISO" type="isAdaptedTo"/><relation target="SpecThesauri" type="isPartOf"/></version></part><part id="SpecThesauri-Part2"><version id="SpecThesauri-2" status="Proof of a new International Standard"><titleStmt><title>Information and documentation — Thesauri and interoperability with other vocabularies — Part 2: 
                    Interoperability with other vocabularies</title><respStmt id="pThes6"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC46-SC9-WG8">ISO/TC 46/SC 9/WG 8</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO/PRF 25964-2</versionNumber><date>2012-12-03</date><info type="description"><p>The second part of the standard is concerned with the issues of the mapping between thesauri and other 
                    types of vocabulary, such as classification schemes, file plans, taxonomies, subject heading schemes, ontologies, name 
                    authority lists, synonym rings, etc. Furthermore it offers guidelines on handling mappings data and models for mapping. </p></info><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecThesauri" type="isPartOf"/></version></part></spec>