<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecHyTime" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicMarkupLanguage" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Information technology — Hypermedia/Time-based Structuring Language</title><abbr>HyTime</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Linking</scope><keyword>hypertext</keyword><keyword>SGML</keyword><keyword>XLink</keyword><info type="description"><p>HyTime stands for Hypermedia/Time-based Structuring Language. It is a markup language used for encoding 
            hyperlinks and other multimedia structures in XML documents. Since 1992 the HyTime is an ISO 10744 Standard providing a hyperlink and addressing mechanism.</p><p>Currently the HyTime is not widely used, but it is very important for the processing of SGML and XML-based Hypermedia technology. 
            In the Hytime, metadata can be associated with a link. Links can be extended to refer to a location outside the linked 
            resources. Furthermore, it is possible to create not only the both unidirectional and bi-directional 
            links but also the links among more than two resources.</p><p>At the first sight, it seems that HyTime is similar to XLink. The similarity in abstract linking models between the two techniques allows the translation 
            from HyTime-based links to XLink-based links. Although both techniques have essentially the same linking 
            structures and semantics, there are significant differences between HyTime and XLink. Firstly, there are a few syntax differences. Secondly,
            unlike XLink, HyTime can provide any form of indirect addressing. XLink is most appropriate for Web-based delivery 
            and therefore not ideal for indirect addressing.</p></info><version id="SpecHyTime-1" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><respStmt id="lgwXlk"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-JTC1-SC34-WG3">ISO(IEC)/JTC 1/SC 34/WG 3</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO/IEC 10744:1992</versionNumber><date>1992-10-01</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.html</address></version><version id="SpecHyTime-2" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><respStmt id="oiqwBt"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-JTC1-SC34-WG3">ISO/IEC JTC 1/SC 34/WG 3</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO/IEC 10744:1997</versionNumber><date>1997-08-29</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.html</address><relation target="SpecHyTime-1" type="isReVersionOf"/><relation target="SpecSGML" type="isApplicationOf"/></version></spec>