<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecKAF" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicSynAnn" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>KYOTO Annotation Format</title><abbr>KAF</abbr></titleStmt><scope>annotation format</scope><info type="description"><p>KAF is a layered annotation format, based on XML. The annotation is stand-off, meaning that the
            original source document remains unchanged and is kept read-only. KAF provides annotation layers
            for basic natural language processing and is open to extensions with other annotation layers needed
            by specific applications, which may be standardized later on. If a process adds information which
            cannot be held by existing layers, a layer of annotation is added. Layers may be linked by means of
            references from one layer to items in another (lower level) layer. Any previous layers remain intact
            and can still be used by other processes.</p><p>KAF as developed within the EU Knowledge Yielding Ontologies for Transition-based Organization (KYOTO) 
            project. It is compatible with LAF (ISO Linguistic Annotation Framework) but imposes a more specific
            standardization of the annotation format itself. KAF can be seen as a multi-layer format for text annotation: 
            the first two layers, explicitly dedicated to representing morphosyntactic and syntactic information, 
            are inspired by MAF and SynAF and are implemented “over” the semantic layer. For semantic annotation, 
            the ISO community provides SemAF which is especially dedicated to the representation of events and time. 
            KAF layers are to be seen as dialects of the ISO standards, yet
            maintaining (different degrees of) mappability to them. The KYOTO dialects do not corrupt the
            compliance with ISO standards and their underlying philosophy; instead, they are in line with the
            strategy in ISO which provides high-level models (meta-models) able to be adapted, tailored and
            implemented according to specific needs.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct id="kyoto" type="conferencePaper"><analytic><title>KAF: a generic semantic annotation format</title><author><forename>Wauter</forename><surname>Bosma</surname></author><author><forename>Piek</forename><surname>Vossen</surname></author><author><forename>Aitor</forename><surname>Soroa</surname></author><author><forename>German</forename><surname>Rigau</surname></author><author><forename>Maurizio</forename><surname>Tesconi</surname></author><author><forename>Andrea</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></author><author><forename>Monica</forename><surname>Monachini</surname></author><author><forename>Carlo</forename><surname>Aliprandi</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Generative Approaches to the Lexicon GL 2009</title><imprint><pubPlace>Pisa, Italy</pubPlace><date>2009</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><relation target="SpecMaf" type="isInspiredBy"/><relation target="SpecSynAF" type="isInspiredBy"/><version id="SpecKAF-2009"><titleStmt><abbr internal="yes">KAF 2009</abbr><respStmt><resp>Author</resp><name>Wauter Bosma</name><name>Piek Vossen</name><name>Aitor Soroa</name><name>German Rigau</name><name>Maurizio Tesconi</name><name>Andrea Marchetti</name><name>Monica Monachini</name><name>Carlo Aliprandi</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2009</date><address type="URL">http://kyoto-project.eu/</address></version></spec>