<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecDSSSL" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicTransformation TopicFormatting" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Document Style Semantics and Specification Language</title><abbr>DSSSL</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Transforming and Formatting SGML-annotated instances</scope><info type="description"><p>The Document Style Semantics and Specification Language (DSSSL) was developed by ISO as a language for transforming and 
            formatting both printed and electronic SGML-encoded documents. DSSSL defines four languages (i.e. transformation language, 
            style language, expression language and query language) for changing, formatting and transforming SGML documents. All the four languages 
            are declarative and are not intended to be complete programming languages, although they contain constructions normally associated with such languages.</p><ul><li>The transformation language is used to transform an SGML document to another SGML-based representation 
                (represented by zero or more SGML documents), according to a given DTD. The result of the transformation process can be used as an input of a formatting process.</li><li>The style language allows users to specify the types of formatting to be applied to various objects during composition, layout, 
                and pagination, and supports a wide range of typographic features. The standardization of formatting semantics is provided through 
                a set of basic structures known as flow objects and an associated set of formatting characteristics that are applied to those objects</li><li>The expression language is the basis of all other three DSSSL language and is a programming language with a SCHEME-like syntax. 
                Unlike a full SCHEME, it is side-effect-free.</li><li>The core query language (Standard Document Query Language, SDQL) is a part of both the transformation language and the style language. It 
                is used to navigate in the tree-like structure of SGML-encoded documents, and to get a path to the relevant parts in a transformation process.</li></ul></info><version id="SpecDSSSL-IS" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><title>Information Technology — Processing Languages – Document Style Semantics and Specification Language (DSSSL)</title><abbr>DSSSL</abbr><respStmt id="kmy3fB"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-JTC1-SC34-WG2">ISO(IEC)/JTC 1/SC 34/WG 2</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO/IEC 10179:1996</versionNumber><date>1996</date><info type="recReading"><ul><li>Jon Bosak. <a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/pub/sun-info/standards/dsssl/dssslo/dssslo.htm">DSSSL Online Application profile. 
                    Technical report</a>, Sun Microsystems, August, 16 1996.</li></ul></info><info type="description"><p>DSSSL Online was developed as a minimal DSSSL application profile for use in the web.</p></info><relation target="SpecSGML" type="isUsedBy"><info><p>DSSSL can be used to process SGML documents.</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecXPath" type="inspires"><info><p>DSSSL's query language for navigating the representation of SGML documents has introduced the concepts of a tree of nodes, 
                ancestors, children, and the like to XPath.</p></info></relation></version></spec>