<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecXSLFO" standardSettingBody="SBW3C" topic="TopicFormatting" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Extensible Stylesheet Language Formatting Objects</title><abbr>XSL-FO</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Formatting of XML-annotated instances</scope><keyword>markup language</keyword><keyword>XML document formatting</keyword><info type="description"><p>The abbreviation stands for Extensible Stylesheet Language Formatting Objects. The XSL-FO is developed by the World Wide 
            Web Consortium (W3C) and is ranked as a W3C Recommendation.</p><p>XSL-FO is formally called XSL. The reason for this is that first XSL Working Draft contained the language syntax 
            for transforming and formatting XML documents. Sometime later the W3C split the draft into separate Recommendations 
            such XSLT, XSL and XPath. In the new draft of XSL the language for formatting XML documents is left and
            then it is called XSL-FO.</p><p>XSL-FO is a XML based page description language for formatting XML data for output to screen, paper or other media. 
            It can define and design page layout, font style, colors, image rendering and lots more design properties. 
            XSL-FO is used not only for printed documents, but also for design of multimedia documents.</p><p>The important advantage of using XSL-FO is its platform or application independence. With XSL-FO the defined document 
            format remains the same on any screen and any platform.</p><p>For example the combination of XSL-FO and Formatting Objects Processor (FOP) allows the generation of print-ready documents 
            in PDF,  AFP,  Postscript, TIFF and other formats.</p></info><version id="SpecXSLFO1" status="W3C Recommendation"><titleStmt><respStmt id="FWeUtb"><resp>Editor</resp><name>Anders Berglund</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2006-12-05</date><address type="URL">http://www.w3.org/TR/2006/REC-xsl11-20061205/</address>
        <!-- <relation target="SpecXSL" type="isPartOf">
            <p/>
        </relation>--><relation target="SpecXML" type="isBasedOn"><info type="description"><p>XSL-FO is based on XML.</p></info></relation></version></spec>