<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecDolce" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicOntology" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Descriptive Ontology for Linguistic and Cognitive Engineering</title><abbr>DOLCE</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Upper level ontology</scope><info type="description"><p>DOLCE (a Descriptive Ontology for Linguistic and Cognitive Engineering) is the first module of the
            WonderWeb Foundational Ontologies Library. DOLCE is an axiomatic ontology (thus, it is a heavy-
            weight ontology, in contrast to light-weight ontologies, which mainly define taxonomic structures).
            DOLCE is an ontology of particulars. A basic choice made in DOLCE is the so-called multiplicative
            approach: different entities can be co-located in the same space-time. The ontology is developed with
            respect to the OntoClean methodology (Guarino and Welty, 2002). OntoClean is a methodology for
            validating the ontological adequacy of taxonomic relationships. DOLCE is axiomatized in a very
            expressive modal logic, but from it several simplified sub-ontologies are isolated. Such sub-
            ontologies are: DOLCE-LITE which includes 80 classes, 80 properties, 24 axioms represented in
            OWL; DOLCE-Lite-Plus which contains additional extensions in direction to Plans, Information
            Objects, Semiotics, Temporal relations, Social notions, etc. DOLCE UltraLite is a very light version
            of DOLCE, which uses friendly names and comments for classes and properties, has simple
            restrictions for classes. All these ontologies can be seen as lightweight versions of the fully
            axiomitized ontology.</p></info><relation target="SpecOWL" type="uses"/><version id="SpecDolce-2.1"><titleStmt><abbr>DOLCHE-2.1-Lite-Plus</abbr><respStmt><resp>Author</resp><name>Claudio Masolo</name><name>Stefano Borgo</name><name>Aldo Gangemi</name><name>Nicola Guarino</name><name>Alessandro Oltramari</name><name>Luc Schneider</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="minor">2.1</versionNumber><address type="URL">http://www.loa.istc.cnr.it/old/DOLCE.html</address></version></spec>