<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecTMX" topic="TopicMarkupLanguage TopicFileFormats" standardSettingBody="SBLISA" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd">
    <titleStmt>
        <title>Translation Memory eXchange</title>
        <abbr>TMX</abbr>
    </titleStmt>
    <scope>Standard format for importing and exporting translation memories</scope>
    <ClarinRecommendation>
        <recommendation specId="SpecTMX" type="fully recommended"/>
    </ClarinRecommendation>
    <keyword>computer-aided translation</keyword>
    <keyword>format</keyword>
    <keyword>translation memory</keyword>
    <info type="description">
        <p>Translation Memory eXchange (TMX) is an XML based standard for importing and
      exporting translation memories created by computer-aided translation and localization
      tools.</p>
        <p>Since 1998 the standard was originally developed within the Container/Content
      Allowing Reuse (OSCAR) committee at the Localization Industry Standards Association
      (LISA).</p>
        <p>After the insolvency of LISA in 2011, the standard has been put under Creative
      Commons license and is freely available in its currently version 1.4b at the GALA
      homepage.</p>
        <p>The TXM is a standardised format for representation of translation memory data.
      It is widely used in the translation and localization industry to exchange translation memory
      content between various translation data or translation-related tools.</p>
        <p>The TMX specification is defined in two parts:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>"A specification of the format of the container (the higher-level elements
        that provide information about the file as a whole and about entries). In TMX, an entry
        consisting of aligned segments of text in two or more languages is called a Translation Unit
        (the &lt;tu&gt; element).</li>
            <li> A specification of a low-level meta-markup format for the content of a
        segment of translation-memory text. In TMX, an individual &lt;segment&gt; of
        translation-memory text in a particular language is denoted by a seg element." See the
        <a href="http://www.gala-global.org/oscarStandards/tmx/tmx14b.html">TMX 1.4b Specification</a>
        for more details. </li>
        </ul>
    </info>
    <relation target="SpecSRX-LISA" type="uses"/>
    <version id="SpecTMX-LISA">
        <titleStmt>
            <title>TMX Specification</title>
            <abbr internal="yes">TMX-2005</abbr>
            <respStmt id="pTMX02">
                <resp>Editor</resp>
                <name type="org" id="SBLISA">LISA</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <versionNumber type="major">1.4b</versionNumber>
        <date>2005-04-26</date>
        <address type="URL">http://www.gala-global.org/oscarStandards/tmx/</address>
        <relation target="SpecSRX" type="uses">
            <info type="description">
                <p>SRX defines how the translation units have been segmented and was built as an
          addition to TXM.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
        <relation target="SpecXML" type="isBasedOn"/>
    </version>
    <asset>
        <a href="../doc/Example_TMX.tmx">Example_TMX.tmx</a>
    </asset>
</spec>