<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecUnicode" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicCharacterEncoding" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>The Unicode Standard</title><abbr internal="yes">Unicode</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Standard for character encoding of text documents</scope><ClarinRecommendation><recommendation specId="SpecUnicode" type="fully recommended"/></ClarinRecommendation><keyword>international character</keyword><keyword>character encoding</keyword><keyword>character set</keyword><keyword>character</keyword><keyword>UCS</keyword><keyword>UTF-8</keyword><info type="description"><p>Unicode is an international standard developed by the Unicode Consortium, that defines nearly every character used in all written languages of the world. 
            The first version of the standard was published in 1991 and covered over 7000 characters. Since the number of characters has increased 
            significantly, currently Unicode contains 112956 different characters of the modern world's language (alphabetic scripts of Europe, the Middle East, 
            Asia and Africa), ancient language (such as Latin, Sanskrit, classical Greek) and many other archaic and historic scripts. Furthermore, the 
            standard encodes many important symbol sets, punctuation marks, mathematical symbols, technical symbols, geometric shapes, dingbats, and emoji.</p><p>Unicode may be seen as a character superset. It combines the character sets represented in many international and national standards of 
            ISO, ANSI/NISO and so on. It also includes character sets from Adobe, Apple, Fujitsu, IBM, Lotus, Microsoft and much more. Therefore, the Unicode 
            Standard offers the most complete and one of the largest character set in the world. Nearly all characters are encoded in Unicode, unambiguously 
            defined and represented independent of any computer system or application used.</p><p>Unicode deﬁnes a name and a numerical value for each character, in three encoding forms: a 32-bit form (UTF-32), a 16-bit form (UTF-16), and an 
            8-bit form (UTF-8). These various forms make it easy to transform data in a byte, word or double word format.</p><p>The character codes of the Unicode Standard and the standard ISO/IEC 10646 (Universal Character Set) are identical and fully compatible with each other.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct id="rec96L" type="onlineSource"><monogr><title>The Unicode Standard: Version 7.0 – Core Specification</title><author type="organisation"><name>The Unicode Consortium</name></author><ref type="url">http://www.unicode.org/versions/Unicode7.0.0/</ref><imprint><date>2014</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><relation target="SpecUCS" type="isSimilarTo"><info type="description"><p>The Unicode character set is codepoint-for-codepoint identical to ISO/IEC 10646 (UCS).</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecEAF" type="uses"><info><p>The textual content of annotations in EAF is encoded in Unicode.</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecIPA" type="hasPart"><info type="description"><p>The Unicode defines codes for symbols used in the IPA</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecLMF" type="isUsedBy"><info type="description"><p>LMF uses the Unicode.</p></info></relation><version id="SpecUnicode-7.0" status="final"><titleStmt><title>The Unicode Standard: Version 7.0 – Core Specification</title><abbr>Unicode 7.0</abbr><respStmt id="pkV001"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org">The Unicode Consortium</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">7.0</versionNumber><date>2014-10-08</date></version></spec>