<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecDOL" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicKnowledgeRepresentation TopicOntology" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Distributed Ontology Language</title><abbr>DOL</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Standardisation of a meta-language for heterogeneous ontology representation</scope><keyword>meta-language</keyword><keyword>ontology</keyword><keyword>knowledge representation</keyword><keyword>distributed ontology language</keyword><keyword>OntoIOp</keyword><keyword>ontology languages</keyword><keyword>syntax</keyword><keyword>semantics</keyword><info type="description"><p>The Distributed Ontology Language (DOL) is a standardisation of a meta-language for heterogeneous ontology representation and is currently 
            under development within the ISO standard OntoIOp.</p><p>The DOL is not just another ontology language such as OWL, DAML+OL, etc., but it also provides a meta-level framework to express 
            logically heterogeneous and distributed ontologies with prices semantics and proof theory and with linking between ontologies, 
            annotations, and the documentations of ontologies. The standard specifies syntax, semantics, and conformance criteria.</p><p>The ontology structure can be defined in various formalisms. Each of them supports its own features and satisfies 
            the requirements for specific purposes of an ontology. The problem comes when the ontology must be used in another system supporting 
            some other formalisms. DOL allows users to use their own preferred ontology formalism and makes it interoperable with other 
            DOL-conforming ontology formalisms. DOL is the first language that systematically supports this property.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct id="pDOL06" type="conferencePaper"><analytic><title>Three Semantics for the Core of the Distributed Ontology Language</title><author><forename>Till</forename><surname>Mossakowski</surname></author><author><forename>Oliver</forename><surname>Kutz</surname></author><author><forename>Christoph</forename><surname>Lange</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>7th International Conference on Formal Ontology in Information Systems (FOIS)</title><imprint><pubPlace>Graz, Austria</pubPlace><date>2012</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct><biblStruct id="pDOL07" type="conferencePaper"><analytic><title>The Distributed Ontology Language (DOL): 
                    Ontology Integration and Interoperability Applied to Mathematical Formalization</title><author><forename>Christoph</forename><surname>Lange</surname></author><author><forename>Oliver</forename><surname>Kutz</surname></author><author><forename>Till</forename><surname>Mossakowski</surname></author><author><forename>Michael</forename><surname>Gruninger</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>Conference on Intelligent Computer Mathematics (CICM), Systems and Projects track</title><imprint><pubPlace>Bremen, Germany</pubPlace><date>2012</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><version id="SpecDOL-L" status="Working Draft"><titleStmt><respStmt id="pDOL04"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC3">ISO/TC 37/SC 3/WG 3</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2011-06-28</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecOntoIOp" type="isUsedBy"><info type="description"><p>DOL is a language for representing distributed knowledge in ontologies.</p></info></relation></version></spec>