<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecThesauri-IFLA" standardSettingBody="SBIFLA" topic="TopicThesaurus TopicControlledVocabulary" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Guidelines for Multilingual Thesauri</title><abbr internal="yes">Multilingual Thesaurus</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Guidelines for building, management and using of thesauri</scope><keyword>Thesaurus</keyword><keyword>Vocabulary</keyword><keyword>Information retrieval</keyword><keyword>Data representation</keyword><info type="description"><p>The Guidelines for Multilingual Thesauri was established in 2009 by the Working Group on Guidelines for Multilingual Thesauri 
            within IFLA. The purpose of these document guidelines is to describe the structure and the principle of building multilingual thesauri.</p><p>On the one hand, the document provides the guidelines for building a new multilingual thesaurus with two different building approaches: 
            According to the first approach, the build of the thesaurus starts with one language. After the termination another language or 
            other languages can be added to it. The second approach starts building a new thesaurus with several languages at the same time.</p><p>On the other hand, the document provides guidelines for building a new thesaurus by merging or linking existing thesauri.</p><p>The Guidelines complements the already existing standards for controlled vocabularies such as IFLA's Principles Underlying Subject 
            Heading Languages (SHLs) and the ANSI/NISO Z39.19-2005 (Guidelines for the Construction, Format, and Management of Monolingual 
            Controlled Vocabularies).</p><p>The Guidelines are on the Web Page of IFLA free available.</p></info><version id="SpecThesaurus-IFLA-1"><titleStmt><respStmt id="paTh06"><resp>Editor</resp><name>Working Group on Guidelines for Multilingual Thesauri</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2009</date><address>http://www.ifla.org/publications/ifla-professional-reports-115</address><relation target="SpecCV-NISO" type="complements"/></version></spec>