<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecWordSeg" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicGenAnn TopicSegmentation" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd" display="show"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Word segmentation of written texts</title><abbr internal="yes">WordSeg</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Standard for word segmentation of written texts</scope><keyword>tokenization</keyword><keyword>word segmentation</keyword><keyword>word</keyword><keyword>segmentation</keyword><keyword>word segmentation unit</keyword><info type="description"><p>Word segmentation is the process of identifying word boundaries in a given text. It is often used as preprocessing step in the 
            context of many NLP tasks such as linguistic annotation, speech recognition, information extraction, machine translation, etc.</p><p> Although the area of word segmentation processing has been relatively well researched in recent years, it remains a nontrivial problem. 
            The complexity results from the fact, that not all languages, such as English, German, French and other languages using some form 
            of the Latin or Cyrillic alphabet, have importers and certain criteria for a word delimiter such as space character. The languages 
            such as Chinese, Japanese or Thai, which have an ideographic writing system, pose a particular problem in word segmentation. 
            There is no word delimiter between words in written sentences.</p><p>The goal of the multiple part standard ISO 24614 is to standardize the word segmentation in a written 
            language whose word boundaries cannot be fully identified by typographic properties.</p></info><part id="SpecWordSeg-Part1"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Word segmentation of written texts — Part 1: Basic concepts and general principles</title><abbr>WordSeg-1</abbr></titleStmt><version id="SpecWordSegBasic" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr>WordSeg-1-2010</abbr><respStmt id="cqz3DA"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG6">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 2 (since 2011, WG 6)</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 24614-1:2010</versionNumber><date>2010-10-25</date><info type="description"><p>The first part of the standard 24614-1:2010 describes the basic concepts and general principles of word segmentation. 
                    The standard offers language-independent requirements, recommendations and guidance for segmentation of the written texts into 
                    word segmentation units (WSU) for monolingual and multilingual information processing. It describes the basic framework for 
                    word segmentation as well. All substantial characteristics, principles, components and processes of word segmentation are 
                    described accurately and in detail in this part of the standard.</p></info><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecLMF-IS" type="uses"><info type="description"><p>should be used in close conjunction with</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecTMF-IS" type="uses"><info type="description"><p>should be used in close conjunction with</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecDcr-IS" type="uses"><info type="description"><p>should be used in close conjunction with</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecMaf-IS" type="uses"><info type="description"><p>should be used in close conjunction with</p></info></relation><relation target="SpecWordSeg" type="isPartOf"/></version></part><part id="SpecWordSeg-Part2"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Word segmentation of written texts — Part 2: 
                Word segmentation for Chinese, Japanese and Korean</title><abbr internal="yes">WordSeg-2</abbr></titleStmt><version id="SpecWordSegCJK" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr internal="yes">WordSeg-2-2011</abbr><respStmt id="kmy2fB"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG6">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 6</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 24614-2:2011</versionNumber><date>2011-08-25</date><info type="description"><p>The second part of the standard is the language-specific, which deals with Chinese, Japanese and Korean languages. 
                    The standard defines word segmentation unit (WSU) for Chinese, Japanese and Korean, provides the general rules for identifying
                    WSU in the above mentioned languages and specifies rules for identifying WSU in each of these three languages as well.</p><p>In this manner, the standard gives a review of the similarities and differences between the languages and additionally explains
                    its implications on the word segmentation and describes it in practical guidelines.</p></info><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecWordSeg" type="isPartOf"/></version></part><part id="SpecWordSeg-Part3"><titleStmt><title>Language resource management — Word segmentation of written texts — Part 3: Thai, Hindi, Vietnamese, and other 
                related languages</title><abbr internal="yes">WordSeg-3</abbr></titleStmt><version id="SpecWordSegOther" status="Preliminary Work Item"><titleStmt><abbr internal="yes">WordSeg-3-2004</abbr><respStmt id="hal3OD"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG6">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 6</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO/PWI 24614-3</versionNumber><date>2004-11-05</date><info type="description"><p>The scope of the third part of standard is to describe the South and Southeast Asian languages and to specify
                    the general rules for their word segmentation. </p></info><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address><relation target="SpecWordSeg" type="isPartOf"/></version></part></spec>