<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecIPA" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicCharacterEncoding TopicFormatting" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd">
    <titleStmt>
        <title>International Phonetic Alphabet</title>
        <abbr>IPA</abbr>
    </titleStmt>
    <scope>A standardization of phonetic and phonemic transcription of language</scope>
    <keyword>Unicode</keyword>
    <keyword>phonetic annotation</keyword>
    <keyword>oral language</keyword>
    <keyword>transcription</keyword>
    <info type="description">
        <p>The International Phonetic Alphabet (IPA) has been developed since 1886 by the
            International Phonetic Association and standardizes the set of symbols for
            representation of sounds in written form for almost all world languages. Primarily, IPA
            was developed based on the Roman alphabet, but then it contains some letters and
            additional symbols from other scripts. </p>
        <p>Each IPA symbol consists of one or more elements (letters, diacritics and prosody marks)
            and is designed to represent only those qualities of speech that are distinctive
            (characteristics that show the significant differences between sounds) in spoken
            language, such as phonemes, intonations, separation of word and syllables. IPA does not
            define symbols describing information such as clicks, pops, gnashing of teeth; spoken
            rapidly or lisping; transcription of atypical speech, but there are extensions to IPA
            symbols that cover the transcription of such sounds. </p>
        <p> IPA is widely used in all areas where the analysis of the oral speech is focused on
            lexicography, linguistics, translation, speech-language pathology.</p>
    </info>
    <relation target="SpecUnicode" type="isPartOf">
        <info type="description">
            <p>The Unicode defines codes for symbols used in the IPA</p>
        </info>
    </relation>
    <relation target="SpecUCS" type="isPartOf">
        <info type="description">
            <p>The UCS contains an IPA section</p>
        </info>
    </relation>
    <version id="SpecIPA-2005">
        <titleStmt>
            <abbr internal="yes">IPA-2005</abbr>
            <respStmt>
                <resp>Editor</resp>
                <name type="org">The International Phonetic Association</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <date>2005</date>
        <address>https://www.langsci.ucl.ac.uk/ipa/index.html</address>
    </version>
</spec>