<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecSumo" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicOntology" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Suggested Upper Merged Ontology</title><abbr>SUMO</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Upper level ontology</scope><info type="description"><p>The Suggested Upper Merged Ontology (SUMO) is a free, formal upper ontology with many
            associated tools, translations, explanatory documents and domain ontologies. It is owned by IEEE. 
            SUMO and all domain
            ontologies consist of 20,000 terms and 60,000 axioms. These consist of SUMO itself, the MId-Level
            Ontology (MILO), and ontologies of Communications, Countries and Regions, Distributed
            computing, Economy, Finance, Engineering components, Geography, Government, Military, North
            American Industrial Classification System, People, Physical elements, Transnational Issues,
            Transportation, Viruses, World Airports A-K, World Airports L-Z. All terms are formally defined.
            Meanings are not dependent on a particular inference implementation. An inference and ontology
            management system however is provided. An additional system that supports visual editing, and
            does a better job of displaying the ontologies, especially in non-Western languages is the KSMSA
            system. SUMO is the only formal ontology (according to the website) that has been mapped to the
            entire WordNet lexicon. SUMO is written in the SUO-KIF language.
        </p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct type="conferencePaper"><analytic><title>Toward a Standard Upper Ontology</title><author><forename>I.</forename><surname>Niles</surname></author><author><forename>A.</forename><surname>Pease</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Formal Ontology in Information Systems (FOIS-2001)</title><editor><forename>Chris</forename><surname>Welty</surname></editor><editor><forename>Barry</forename><surname>Smith</surname></editor><imprint><biblScope type="pp">2-9</biblScope><date>2001</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><version id="SpecSumo-2000"><titleStmt><abbr>SUMO 2000</abbr><respStmt><resp>Editor</resp><name>Adam Pease</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2000</date><address type="URL">http://www.adampease.org/OP/</address></version></spec>