<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecSimple" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicOntology" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>SIMPLE Core Ontology</title><abbr>SIMPLE</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Upper level ontology</scope><info type="description"><p>SIMPLE Core Ontology (Lenci et al., 2000) is created within SIMPLE Project for creation of
            semantic dictionaries for 12 European languages. The role of the SIMPLE Core ontology is to cluster
            the meaning of the words in the dictionaries. The meaning is represented via means of lexical
            templates, where each template is connected to a concept in the ontology and the fields of the
            template corresponds to the restrictions over the concepts expressed in the ontology. The lexical
            model of SIMPLE project extends the Generative Lexicon (GL) model. The SIMPLE project
            developed further the GL model by constructing an upper ontology that reflects the four qualia roles
            of GL model – Formal, Constitutive, Telic, and Agentive. The SIMPLE Core Ontology can be seen
            as a set of four interconnected ontologies: One ontology consisting of a hierarchy of concepts,
            additionally connected to other concepts via relations and functions. This sub-ontology corresponds
            to Formal qualia role. The other three ontologies consist of hierarchies of relations. Each of the
            relational ontologies corresponds to one of the qualia roles. Additionally, the concept ontology is
            extended with complex types which consist of two (or more) concepts which represent colocalized
            entities (see also DOLCE). The role of the complex types is to represent the regular polysemy in the
            lexicon. The ontology is represented as taxonomy of concepts and flat lists of relations. The SIMPLE
            Ontology contains 193 concepts and about 60 relations.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct id="kyoto" type="journalArticle"><analytic><title>SIMPLE: A General Framework for the Development of Multilingual Lexicons</title><author><forename>Alessandro</forename><surname>Lenci</surname></author><author><forename>Nuria</forename><surname>Bel</surname></author><author><forename>Federica</forename><surname>Busa</surname></author><author><forename>Nicoletta</forename><surname>Calzolari</surname></author><author><forename>Elisabetta</forename><surname>Gola</surname></author><author><forename>Monica</forename><surname>Monachini</surname></author><author><forename>Antoine</forename><surname>Ogonowski</surname></author><author><forename>Ivonne</forename><surname>Peters</surname></author><author><forename>Wim</forename><surname>Peters</surname></author><author><forename>Nilda</forename><surname>Ruimy</surname></author><author><forename>Marta</forename><surname>Villegas</surname></author><author><forename>Antonio</forename><surname>Zampolli</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>International Journal of Lexicography</title><ref type="url">http://ijl.oxfordjournals.org/content/13/4/249.short</ref><imprint><biblScope type="pp">249-263</biblScope><biblScope type="vol">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue">4</biblScope><date>2000</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><version id="SpecSimple-2000"><titleStmt><abbr internal="yes">SIMPLE 2000</abbr><respStmt><resp>Author</resp><name>Alessandro Lenci</name><name>Nuria Bel</name><name>Federica Busa</name><name>Nicoletta Calzolari</name><name>Elisabetta Gola</name><name>Monica Monachini</name><name>Antoine Ogonowski</name><name>Ivonne Peters</name><name>Wim Peters</name><name>Nilda Ruimy</name><name>Marta Villegas</name><name>Antonio Zampolli</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2000</date></version></spec>