<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecCes" standardSettingBody="SBEAGLES" topic="TopicGenAnn" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd">
    <titleStmt>
        <title>Corpus Encoding Standard</title>
        <abbr>CES/XCES</abbr>
    </titleStmt>
    <scope>corpus annotation</scope>
    <keyword>corpus</keyword>
    <keyword>CES</keyword>
    <keyword>corpus encoding</keyword>
    <keyword>CES</keyword>
    <keyword>XCES</keyword>
    <info type="description">
        <p/>
    </info>
    <version id="SpecCes4-1" status="final">
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Corpus Encoding Standard</title>
            <abbr>CES</abbr>
            <respStmt id="IKdc87">
                <resp>Author</resp>
                <name type="person">Nancy Ide</name>
                <name type="person">Greg Priest-Dorman</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <versionNumber type="major">4.1</versionNumber>
        <date>1996-10-14</date>
        <info type="description">
            <p>CES is an encoding standard for corpus annotation. It was developed within the
                framework of the EAGLES (Expert Advisory Group on Language Engineering Standards)
                project. The aim of the CES is to provide a unitary coding standard for linguistic
                corpus annotation. The CES can be used to encode corpora as resources for natural
                language processing.</p>
            <p>SGML (ISO 8879:1986 Standard Generalized Markup Language) was the foundation of the
                CES. Beside the SGML, TEI (Text Encoding Initiative) Guidelines were taken into
                account for the development of the CES. Like the TEI, the CES standardizes the
                document structure (e.g. title, caption, break) or document info (metadata). In
                addition to that, the CES standardizes the linguistic annotation of a text (e.g.
                morpho-syntactic tagging, parallel text alignment, prosody, phonetic transcription,
                etc.). TEI P3 and the CES are compatible to each other, so they can be used side by
                side. As an XML-based version of the CES, XCES (Corpus Encoding Standard for XML)
                has also been developed .</p>
            <p>The CES can be applied in monolingual, multi-lingual and parallel corpora.</p>
        </info>
        <features>
            <fs>
                <f name="metaLanguage">
                    <symbol value="SGML"/>
                </f>
                <f name="constraintLanguage">
                    <symbol value="DTD"/>
                </f>
                <f name="grammarClass">
                    <symbol value="LTG"/>
                </f>
                <f name="formalModel">
                    <symbol value="Tree"/>
                </f>
                <f name="notation">
                    <symbol value="Standoff"/>
                </f>
                <f name="multipleHierarchies">
                    <fs>
                        <f name="support">
                            <binary value="yes"/>
                        </f>
                        <f name="item">
                            <vColl>
                                <string>standoff annotation</string>
                            </vColl>
                        </f>
                    </fs>
                </f>
            </fs>
        </features>
        <address type="URL">http://www.cs.vassar.edu/CES/</address>
        <relation target="SpecSGML" type="isBasedOn">
            <info>
                <p> CES is based on the SGML.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
        <relation target="SpecTeiP3" type="isApplicationOf">
            <info>
                <p>CES is an application of the SGML-based TEI P3 using the TEI modification
                    layer.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
        <relation target="SpecXces104" type="isVersionOf">
            <info>
                <p>CES is the SGML ancestor of the XML-based XCES.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
    </version>
    <version id="SpecXces104" status="final" usedInCLARINCenter="CLARIN-PL IDS">
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Corpus Encoding Standard in XML</title>
            <abbr>XCES</abbr>
            <respStmt id="yULgPs">
                <resp>Editor</resp>
                <name type="person">Nancy Ide</name>
                <name type="person">Patrice Bonhomme</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <versionNumber type="major">1.0.4</versionNumber>
        <date>2008-06-20</date>
        <info type="description">
            <p>XCES is the XML version of the Corpus Encoding Standard (CES). It was developed by
                the Department of Computer Science, Vassar College, and Equipe Langue et Dialogue,
                LORIA/CNRS, for the simple reason that XML is the standard for data representation
                and exchange on the World Wide Web. Some of the aims of this conversion were to
                offer a state-of-the-art representation of the corpus data and to be accessible for
                the language engineering community as well.</p>
            <p>XCES offers DTDs and XML schemas for encoding basic document structure and linguistic
                annotation. The implementation of CES in XML allows not only the morpho-syntactic
                annotation but also the syntactic annotation. With the aid of XLink und XPointer,
                XCES gives more complex and superior method to refer to the standoff annotated
                corpus data, in contrast to the SGML based CES.</p>
            <p>Furthermore XCES currently includes XML Schemas for validation and some XSLT scripts
                to transform into HTML document.</p>
            <p>XCES is developed continually and planned be compliant with TEI P5. Currently the
                stages of development between the TEI Guidelines and XCES are so large that the TEI
                Guidelines P5 cannot be used in XCES.</p>
        </info>
        <features>
            <fs>
                <f name="metaLanguage">
                    <symbol value="XML"/>
                </f>
                <f name="constraintLanguage">
                    <symbol value="XSD"/>
                </f>
                <f name="grammarClass">
                    <symbol value="LTG"/>
                </f>
                <f name="formalModel">
                    <symbol value="Graph"/>
                </f>
                <f name="notation">
                    <symbol value="Standoff"/>
                </f>
                <f name="multipleHierarchies">
                    <fs>
                        <f name="support">
                            <binary value="yes"/>
                        </f>
                        <f name="item">
                            <vColl>
                                <string>standoff annotation</string>
                            </vColl>
                        </f>
                    </fs>
                </f>
            </fs>
        </features>
        <address type="URL">http://www.xces.org/</address>
        <relation type="isVersionOf" target="SpecCes4-1">
            <info>
                <p>XCES is the XML instantiation of CES.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
        <relation target="SpecLaf-IS" type="hasPart"/>
        <!--relation target="SpecIDS-XCES" type="isBasedOn"/-->
        <relation target="SpecXML" type="isApplicationOf">
            <info>
                <p>XCES is an application of the Extensible Markup Language (XML), for instance it
                    uses the XML syntax.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
        <relation target="SpecXSD" type="isApplicationOf">
            <info>
                <p>XCES uses XML Schema 1.0 as a constraint language.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
        <relation target="SpecTei" type="isBasedOn">
            <info type="description">
                <p>The XCES specification is based on the TEI P3 Standard.</p>
            </info>
        </relation>
    </version>
</spec>