<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecISOLangCodes" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicControlledVocabulary" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Codes for the representation of names of languages</title><abbr>ISO Language Codes</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Internationally recognised codes for the representation of languages or language families</scope><ClarinRecommendation><recommendation specId="SpecISOLangCodes-Part1" type="acceptable"><alternatives><alternative specId="SpecISOLangCodes-Part3"/></alternatives></recommendation><recommendation specId="SpecISOLangCodes-Part2" type="not recommended"><alternatives><alternative specId="SpecISOLangCodes-Part3"/></alternatives></recommendation><recommendation specId="SpecISOLangCodes-Part3" type="fully recommended"/></ClarinRecommendation><keyword>Controlled vocabulary</keyword><keyword>names of languages</keyword><keyword>names of language families</keyword><info type="description"><p>The international standard for language codes (ISO 639) is developed as a multi part standard and provides the internationally recognised two 
            and three alphabetic codes for the representation of natural languages or language families and groups.</p><p>The language codes are widely used for example in applications for terminology, lexicography, linguistics, information and documentation 
            (e.g. for libraries, information services, and publishers). The language codes standardisation were designed for all working areas (e.g. 
            libraries, information services, and publishers), where the indication of languages is important for data exchange between different 
            databases or computerized systems.
        </p></info><part id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part1"><titleStmt><title>Codes for the representation of names of languages — Part 1: Alpha-2 code</title><abbr internal="yes">Language Codes Part 1</abbr></titleStmt><info type="description"><p>"This part of ISO 639 provides a code consisting of language code elements comprising two-letter language identifiers for the representation 
                of names of languages. The language identifiers according to this part of ISO 639 were devised originally for use in terminology, 
                lexicography and linguistics, but may be adopted for any application requiring the expression of language in two-letter coded form, 
                especially in computerized systems. The alpha-2 code was devised for practical use for most of the major languages of the world 
                that are not only most frequently represented in the total body of the world's literature, but which also comprise a considerable 
                volume of specialized languages and terminologies. Additional language identifiers are created when it becomes apparent that 
                a significant body of documentation written in specialized languages and terminologies exists. Languages designed exclusively 
                for machine use, such as computer-programming languages, are not included in this code." <a href="http://www.iso.org">Abstract, ISO 639-1:2002</a></p></info><version id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part1-2002" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr>ISO 639-1:2002</abbr></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 639-1:2002</versionNumber><date>2013-07-09</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.htm</address><relation target="SpecDINLangCodes" type="isUsedBy"/></version></part><part id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part2"><titleStmt><title>Codes for the representation of names of languages — Part 2: Alpha-3 code</title><abbr>Language Codes Part 2</abbr></titleStmt><info type="description"><p>Similar to the first part, the second part of the ISO 639 standard provides language codes for the representation of names of languages 
                and language groups. The first and the second parts of the standard define the codes for a language, but in two different letter code sets: 
                ISO 639-1 has the two letter code set and the ISO 639-2 with three letter codes set.</p></info><version id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part2-1998" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr>ISO 639-2:1998</abbr></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 639-2:1998</versionNumber><date>2010-07-20</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.htm</address></version></part><part id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part3"><titleStmt><title>Codes for the representation of names of languages — Part 3: Alpha-3 code for comprehensive coverage of languages</title><abbr internal="yes">Language Codes Part 3</abbr></titleStmt><info type="description"><p>"ISO 639-3:2007 provides a code, published by the Registration Authority of ISO 639-3, consisting of language code elements comprising 
                three-letter language identifiers for the representation of languages. The language identifiers according to this ISO 639-3:2007 
                were devised for use in a wide range of applications, especially in computer systems, where there is potential need to support a 
                large number of the languages that are known to have ever existed. Whereas ISO 639-1 and ISO 639-2 are intended to focus on the
                major languages of the world that are most frequently represented in the total body of the world's literature, ISO 639-3:2007 
                attempts to provide as complete an enumeration of languages as possible, including living, extinct, ancient and constructed 
                languages, whether major or minor, written or unwritten. As a result, ISO 639-3:2007 deals with a very large number of lesser-known 
                languages. Languages designed exclusively for machine use, such as computer-programming languages and reconstructed languages, 
                are not included in this code." <a href="http://www.iso.org">Abstract, ISO 639-3:2007</a></p></info><version id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part3-2007" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr>ISO 639-3:2007</abbr></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 639-3:2007</versionNumber><date>2010-07-20</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.htm</address></version></part><part id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part4"><titleStmt><title>Codes for the representation of names of languages — Part 4: 
                General principles of coding of the representation of names of languages and related entities, and application guidelines</title><abbr internal="yes">Language Codes Part 4</abbr></titleStmt><info type="description"><p>"ISO 639-4:2010 gives the general principles of language coding using the codes that are specified in the other parts of ISO 639 and their 
                combination with other codes. It also lays down guidelines for the use of any combination of the parts of ISO 639.</p><p>The terminology and general descriptions of ISO 639-4 are intended to replace corresponding text of other parts of ISO 639 as 
                relevant in future revisions.</p><p>Relevant metadata for the description of linguistic entities are given, as a framework for databases of linguistic 
                data to support the ISO 639 series." <a href="http://www.iso.org">Abstract, ISO 639-4:2010</a></p></info><version id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part4-2010" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr>ISO 639-4:2010</abbr></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 639-4:2010</versionNumber><date>2010-07-16</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.htm</address></version></part><part id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part5"><titleStmt><title>Codes for the representation of names of languages — Part 5: Alpha-3 code for language families and groups</title><abbr internal="yes">Language Codes Part 5</abbr></titleStmt><info type="description"><p>"ISO 639-5:2008 provides a code consisting of language code elements comprising three-letter language identifiers for the 
                representation of names of living and extinct language families and groups. Languages designed exclusively for machine use, 
                such as computer-programming languages, are not included in this code." <a href="http://www.iso.org">Abstract, ISO 639-5:2008</a></p></info><version id="SpecISOLangCodes-Part5-2008" status="International Standard"><titleStmt><abbr>ISO 639-5:2008</abbr></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">ISO 639-5:2008</versionNumber><date>2011-09-23</date><address type="URL">http://www.iso.org/iso/home.htm</address></version></part></spec>