<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecEAF"
    standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicFileFormats"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd">
    <titleStmt>
        <title>ELAN Annotation Format</title>
        <abbr>EAF</abbr>
    </titleStmt>
    <scope>File format for linguistic annotations of audio and video recordings</scope>
    <ClarinRecommendation>
        <recommendation specId="SpecEAF" type="fully recommended"/>
    </ClarinRecommendation>
    <keyword>Digital archiving</keyword>
    <keyword>ELAN</keyword>
    <keyword>file format</keyword>
    <keyword>annotation format</keyword>
    <keyword>XML schema</keyword>
    <keyword>multimodal annotation</keyword>
    <info type="description">
        <p>The abbreviation EAF stands for ELAN Annotation Format, also known as the EUDICO
            Annotation Format. It was developed by The Language Archive at the Max Planck Institute
            for Psycholinguistics. The ELAN (EUDICO Linguistic Annotator) Tool stores complex
            multi-layered annotations of audio and video recordings in EAF. The annotations in EAF
            are time-aligned and linked to a single point in the timeline of the audio or video
            recordings.</p>
        <p>The EAF specification defines an XML schema and describes the elements and attributes of
            the schema. It is based on a tier-based data model. A tier is a kind of annotation layer
            that groups annotations with same characteristics in user-defined tier objects. For
            example, a tier may contain the orthographic transcription, and another tier the Part of
            Speech annotation of the items corresponding to the former tier. In this way the tiers
            can be represented independent, or can be hierarchically connected and associated with a
            parent tier. Within a tier, annotations can not overlap, but the annotations on one tier
            can overlap with annotations on other tiers.</p>
        <p>Similar to LAF, CES and XCES, EAF uses stand-off annotation. This means, that the primary
            data and annotation are stored in separate files.</p>
        <p>EAF is a multi-purpose format. It can be used not only for linguistic transcription and
            annotation, but also for the annotation of gestures and sign languages. That’s why it is
            more and more recognized, and has been used in a variety of disciplines such as
            linguistics, gesture research, sign language research and behavioural studies.</p>
    </info>
    <info type="recReading">
        <biblStruct id="rec3dl" type="onlineSource">
            <monogr>
                <title>ELAN Annotation Format: EAF (Schema version: 2.8)</title>
                <author type="organisation"
                    ><name>The Language Archive at the Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics Nijmegen</name></author>
                <ref type="url">http://www.mpi.nl/tools/elan/EAF_Annotation_Format_2.8_and_ELAN.pdf</ref>
                <imprint>
                    <pubPlace>The Netherlands</pubPlace>
                    <date>2014</date>
                </imprint>
            </monogr>
        </biblStruct>
    </info>
    <relation target="SpecXML" type="isBasedOn">
        <info type="description">
            <p>The file structure of the document is based on XML.</p>
        </info>
    </relation>
    <relation target="SpecUnicode" type="isBasedOn">
        <info>
            <p>The textual content of annotations is in Unicode.</p>
        </info>
    </relation>
    <version id="SpecEAF-2014" status="final" usedInCLARINCenter="MPI-PL">
        <titleStmt>
            <title>ELAN Annotation Format: EAF</title>
            <abbr>EAF-2014</abbr>
            <respStmt>
                <resp>Editor</resp>
                <name type="org" id="SBOther">MPI-PL (Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics)</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <versionNumber type="major">2.8</versionNumber>
    </version>
</spec>
