<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecFS" standardSettingBody="SBISO" topic="TopicFeatureStructure" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd" display="show">
    <titleStmt>
        <title>Language resource management — Feature structures</title>
        <abbr>Feature structures</abbr>
    </titleStmt>
    <scope>Standards for feature structures representation and system declaration</scope>
    <keyword>data processing</keyword>
    <keyword>data management</keyword>
    <keyword>data representation</keyword>
    <keyword>XML</keyword>
    <keyword>metadata</keyword>
    <info type="description">
        <p/>
    </info>
    <part id="SpecFS-Part1">
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Language resource management — Feature structures — Part 1: Feature structure representation</title>
            <abbr>FSR</abbr>
        </titleStmt>
        <info type="description">
            <p>
                "ISO 24610-1:2006 provides a format for the representation, storage and exchange of feature structures in natural 
                language applications concerned with the annotation, production or analysis of linguistic data. It also defines a 
                computer format for the description of constraints that bear on a set of features, feature values, feature specifications 
                and operations on feature structures, thus offering a means of checking the conformance of each feature structure with 
                regards to a reference specification." 
                (<a href="http://www.iso.org/iso/catalogue_detail.htm?csnumber=37324">Abstract, ISO 24610-1:2006</a>)
            </p>
        </info>
        <version id="SpecFSR" status="International Standard" usedInCLARINCentre="CLARIN-PL1">
            <titleStmt>
                <abbr>FSR-2006</abbr>
                <respStmt id="par2FS">
                    <resp>Editor</resp>
                    <name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG1">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 1</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <versionNumber type="major"> ISO 24610-1:2006</versionNumber>
            <date>2006-04-10</date>
            <address type="URL">http://www.iso.org</address>
        </version>
    </part>
    <part id="SpecFS-Part2">
        <titleStmt>
            <title>Language resource management — Feature structures — Part 2: Feature system declaration</title>
            <abbr>FSD</abbr>
        </titleStmt>
        <info type="description">
            <p>
                "ISO 24610-2:2011 provides a format to represent, store or exchange feature structures in natural language applications, 
                for both annotation and production of linguistic data. It is ultimately designed to provide a computer format to define a 
                type hierarchy and to declare the constraints that bear on a set of feature specifications and operations on feature structures, 
                thus offering means to check the conformance of each feature structure with regards to a reference specification. 
                Feature structures are an essential part of many linguistic formalisms as well as an underlying mechanism for 
                representing the information consumed or produced by and for language engineering applications.</p>
            <p>A feature system declaration (FSD) is an auxiliary file used in conjunction with a certain type of text that makes 
                use of fs (that is, feature structure) elements. The FSD serves four purposes. 1) It provides an encoding by which types and 
                their subtyping and inheritance relationships can be introduced and defined, thus laying the basis for constructing a feature 
                system. 2) It provides a mechanism by which the encoder can list all of the feature names and feature values and give a prose
                description as to what each represents. 3) It provides a mechanism by which type constraints can be declared, against which
                typed feature structures are validated relative to a given theory stated in typed feature logic. These constraints may involve 
                constraints on the range of a feature's value, constraints on which features are permitted within certain types of feature 
                structures, or constraints that prevent the co-occurrence of certain feature-value pairs. The source of these constraints 
                is normally the empirical domain being modelled. 4) It provides a mechanism by which the encoder can define the intended 
                interpretation of underspecified feature structures. This involves defining default values (whether literal or computed) 
                for missing features.</p>
            <p>The scheme described in ISO 24610-2:2011 may be used to document any feature system, but is primarily intended for 
                use with the typed feature structure representation defined in ISO 24610-1. The feature structure representations of 
                ISO 24610-1 specify data structures that are subject to the typing conventions and constraints specified using 
                ISO 24610-2:2011. The feature structure representations of ISO 24610-1 are also used within some of the elements defined 
                in ISO 24610-2:2011." 
                (<a href="http://www.iso.org/iso/catalogue_detail.htm?csnumber=43823">Abstract, ISO 24610-1:2006</a>)
            </p>
        </info>
        <version id="SpecFSD" status="International Standard">
            <titleStmt>
                <abbr internal="yes">FSD-2011</abbr>
                <respStmt id="par4FS">
                    <resp>Editor</resp>
                    <name type="org" id="SBISO-TC37-SC4-WG1">ISO/TC 37/SC 4/WG 1</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <versionNumber type="major">ISO 24610-2:2011</versionNumber>
            <date>2011-09-26</date>
        </version>
    </part>
</spec>