<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecRTF" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicFileFormats" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Rich Text Format</title><abbr>RTF</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Specification of the format for text and graphics interchange</scope><ClarinRecommendation><recommendation specId="SpecRTF" type="acceptable"><alternatives><alternative specId="SpecXHTML"/><alternative specId="SpecTei"/></alternatives></recommendation></ClarinRecommendation><keyword>File format</keyword><keyword>Microsoft Word</keyword><info type="description"><p>Rich Text Format (RTF) is a file format that was developed and standardized by Microsoft Corporation for creating formatted text files. 
            The RTF format is all-purpose and widespread. Almost every word processing program in different operating systems can open, create or 
            edit RTF formatted documents. For this reason, it is often used to transfer formatted text files among several 
            different computer systems using different word processing programs.</p><p> More than a basic text file, the RTF format also contains formatting features, such as text style, size, colour, tables, different 
            fonts and so on. The formatting features are specified by an internal mark-up language. However, RTF does not support all features of a full word processor, like Microsoft Word.</p><p>As Microsoft Word and MS Office are improved continuously and their new versions have been published periodically, the RTF specification has also been revised several times. 
            The first version of the specification was published in 1987. The latest version is 1.9.1 published in 2008.</p></info><version id="SpecRTF-2008" status="final"><titleStmt><title>Rich Text Format Specification Version 1.9.1</title><abbr internal="yes">RTF 1.9.1</abbr><respStmt><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBOther">Microsoft Corporation</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">1.9.1</versionNumber><date>2008-03-20</date><info type="description"><p>The specification RTF 1.9.1 is compatible with the updates introduced in Microsoft Office Word 2007/Word 12.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct id="rec67HS" type="onlineSource"><monogr><title>Rich Text Format (RTF) Specification: Version 1.9.1</title><editor type="organisation"><name>Microsoft Corporation</name></editor><ref type="url">http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=10725</ref><imprint><date>2008</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><asset><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=10725">Specification 1.9.1</a></asset></version></spec>