<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecPennTB" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicSynAnn" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>Penn Treebank (Phrase Structure Treebank)</title><abbr>Penn Treebank</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Syntactic annotation format</scope><info type="description"><p>Penn Treebank format is an annotation format for part-of-speech tagged and syntactically
            parsed corpora. It was developed at the University of Pennsylvania for the Penn
            Treebank. Syntactic dependencies of tree structures are realized by hierarchical
            “bracketing” of words and phrases. Due to that ordering principle, analysis is
            essentially context-free, and non-contiguous structures and dependencies are not
            possible.</p><p>Penn Treebank corpus files do not contain any metadata but only consist of a series of
            annotated sentences. There is no formal specification how tag sets etc. should be
            published. Bracketed structures can be arbitrarily complex, and one bracketed structure
            can nest within another. Brackets are labeled with their syntactical category; every
            bracket has exactly one label (except the bracket which surrounds the entire sentence,
            it has no label). Phrases can contain an unlimited number of elements; its head element
            is not marked explicitly. Penn Treebank uses symbols for different kinds of null
            elements.</p><p>Treebank I bracketing was used until 1992. In 1994, guidelines for a refined bracketing
            format were published. Wishes were to explicitly provide some form of predicate-argument
            structure, to provide richer annotation forms and to mark non-contiguous structures. If
            only the Penn Treebank file format is used and own annotation standards are created, the
            only difference between formats I and II lies in the number of constituent labels and
            the number of tags allowed.</p></info><address type="URL">http://www.cis.upenn.edu/~treebank/</address><version id="SpecPennTB-I"><titleStmt><abbr>Treebank I bracketing</abbr><respStmt><resp>Author</resp><name>Beatrice Santorini</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>1991</date><info type="recReading"><biblStruct type="journalArticle"><analytic><title>Building a Large Annotated Corpus of English: The Penn Treebank</title><author><forename>Mitchell</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></author><author><forename>Mary Ann</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></author><author><forename>Santorini</forename><surname>Beatrice</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>Comput. Linguist.</title><imprint><biblScope type="pp">313-330</biblScope><biblScope type="vol">19</biblScope><publisher>MIT Press</publisher><date>1993</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info></version><version id="SpecPennTB-II"><titleStmt><abbr>Treebank II bracketing</abbr><respStmt><resp>Publisher</resp><name type="org">Linguistic Data Consortium</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>1995</date><info type="recReading"><biblStruct type="conferencePaper"><analytic><title>The Penn Treebank: Annotating Predicate Argument Structure</title><author><forename>Mitchell</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></author><author><forename>Grace</forename><surname>Kim</surname></author><author><forename>Robert</forename><surname>MacIntyre</surname></author><author><forename>Ann</forename><surname>Bies</surname></author><author><forename>Mark</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></author><author><forename>Karen</forename><surname>Katz</surname></author><author><forename>Britta</forename><surname>Schasberger</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>Proceedings of the Workshop on Human Language Technology</title><imprint><biblScope type="pp">114-119</biblScope><publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher><date>1994</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info></version></spec>