<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecDINLangCodes" standardSettingBody="SBDIN" topic="TopicControlledVocabulary" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>DIN Language codes</title><abbr>DIN Language Codes</abbr></titleStmt><scope>Codes for the representation of languages or language families in German language</scope><keyword>Controlled vocabulary</keyword><keyword>names of languages</keyword><keyword>names of language families</keyword><keyword>alpha-2 code</keyword><keyword>alpha-3 code</keyword><keyword>ISO 639-1</keyword><info type="description"><p>The DIN 2335 standard defines a German (two letters long) language code for each language name 
            in ISO 639-1. In some cases when there are more 
            than one German spelling variant for a language name in another language — depending 
            on what kind of transcription or transliteration is used, the standard determines from which 
            variant should the corresponding equivalent be derived. For instance, for the language name 'Swahili' 
            <i>in English:</i>, there are two spelling variants <i>in German:</i> 'Swahili' and 'Suaheli', 
            and in DIN 2335, the german equivalent is 'SW' derived from "Swahili". </p><p>The main criterion for the selection of one corresponding language name, is the use of the
            language name in the German language dictionaries, publications and text corpora.</p><p>Such as ISO 639, the DIN 2335 standard is developed to be used for example in
            applications for terminology, documentation, publication and library. The language codes
            standardisation is applicable for all working areas, where the indication of languages
            is important for data exchange between different databases or computerized systems.</p></info><version id="SpecDINLangCodes-1986" status="National Standard"><titleStmt><title>Language symbols</title><abbr internal="yes">Language symbols-1986</abbr><respStmt id="kjj1DG"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBDIN">NA 105-00-01 AA</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">DIN 2335:1986-10</versionNumber><date>1986</date><relation target="SpecDINLangCodes-2014" type="isRevisedBy"/></version><version id="SpecDINLangCodes-2014" status="Draft National Standard"><titleStmt><title>German language designations for the alpha-2 code according to ISO 639-1</title><abbr internal="yes">DIN Language Codes-2014</abbr><respStmt id="kjj2DG"><resp>Editor</resp><name type="org" id="SBDIN">NA 105-00-01 AA</name></respStmt></titleStmt><versionNumber type="major">DIN 2335:2014-07</versionNumber><date>2014-06-27</date><address type="URL"/><relation target="SpecDINLangCodes-1986" type="isRevisionOf"/><relation target="SpecISOLangCodes" type="isExtendedFrom"/></version></spec>