<spec xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="SpecTriple" standardSettingBody="SBOther" topic="TopicQuery" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/spec.xsd"><titleStmt><title>TRIPLE</title><abbr>TRIPLE</abbr></titleStmt><scope>RDF Query language</scope><keyword>Metadata</keyword><keyword>Knowledge Representation and Reasoning</keyword><keyword>RDF</keyword><keyword>F-Logic</keyword><info type="description"><p>TRIPLE is an RDF query, inference, and transformation language for the Semantic Web.
            TRIPLE formulates queries in an ontology to correspond to a user-specific view. The
            approach is based on maintenance of multiple views expressed in ontologies simpler than
            the domain ontology. This allows users to query heterogeneous data repositories.
            Ontology developers can define view ontologies and corresponding mapping rules. The use
            of the language TRIPLE is useful when not only representation of RDF data is necessary
            but also a definition of views and mappings at the same time. TRIPLE provided an
            infrastructure to evaluate queries issued against the user-specific ontology and in this
            way to realize the view. The view techniques have central importance when creating
            interoperability. TRIPLE has the following overview features: native support for
            resources and namespaces, abbreviations; models (sets of RDF statements); reification;
            rules with bodies; transformations; syntactical extension of Horn Logic; syntactically
            similar to F-Logic; has both ASCII and RDF syntax.</p></info><info type="recReading"><biblStruct type="bookSection"><analytic><title>TRIPLE—A Query, Inference, and Transformation Language for the Semantic Web</title><author><forename>Michael</forename><surname>Sintek</surname></author><author><forename>Stefan</forename><surname>Decker</surname></author></analytic><monogr><title>The Semantic Web — ISWC 2002</title><editor><forename>Ian</forename><surname>Horrocks</surname></editor><editor><forename>James</forename><surname>Hendler</surname></editor><imprint><biblScope type="pp">364-378</biblScope><biblScope type="vol">2342</biblScope><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><date>2002</date></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></info><address type="URL">http://www.dfki.uni-kl.de/frodo/triple/</address><relation target="SpecRDF" type="isApplicationOf"/><version id="SpecTriple-2002"><titleStmt><abbr>triple-20020314</abbr><respStmt><resp>Author</resp><name>Stefan Decker</name><name>Michael Sintek</name></respStmt></titleStmt><date>2002</date></version></spec>