<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/recommendation.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?> 
<recommendation xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/recommendation.xsd">
   <header>
      <lastUpdateCommitID>769a30e1aa1d88ca6ff632af0047b829055fbe76</lastUpdateCommitID>
      <filter>
         <centreID>EKUT</centreID>
      </filter>
      <respStmt>
         <name><!--for multiple curators, use multiple respStmt elements, each with a resp--></name>
         <resp><!--optionally specify the range of responsibility; useful if multiple respStmt are used--></resp>
         <link><!--URI; GitHub page or any other way to id/contact the curator--></link>
         <reviewDate>0001-01-01</reviewDate>
      </respStmt>
      <centre id="EKUT" deposition="1">
         <centreName>Eberhard Karls Universität Tübingen</centreName>
         <!--Tübingen Archive of Language Resources - we need multiple <name> elements! -->
         <registryLink registry="CLARIN" uri="https://centres.clarin.eu/centre/1"/>
         <registryLink registry="Text+" uri="https://registry.text-plus.org/entity/48ad519f-5023-481a-82eb-8e701fda1dee/"/>
         <nodeInfo>
            <ri status="B-centre">CLARIN</ri>
            <ri status="Collections, Lexical Resources">Text+</ri>
         </nodeInfo>
      </centre>
    </header>
   <info xml:lang="en">
      <p>The data of the Tübingen Archive of Language Resources (TALAR) include corpora for spoken
         and written language that are annotated at different levels of linguistic analysis:
         morphology, syntax and semantics. In addition, TALAR hosts lexical resources that are
         closely linked to other lexical and textual resources represented in Text+. The corpora and
         lexical resources are indispensable for data-driven research in both theoretical and
         computational linguistics. The annotations include various grammatical frameworks and
         adhere to the coding standards widely used in the community as well as the coding standards
         of the International Standards Organization (ISO). The TALAR data repository has been
         certified by the Core Trust Seal (CTS) and it has standardized protocols for data ingest.
         TALAR hosts a collection of widely used syntactically annotated corpora, the so-called TüBa
         treebanks for German, English and Japanese. In addition, it gives access to a large number
         of externally developed treebanks as part of the Universal Dependencies project. All
         linguistically annotated corpora of the UniTÜ can be searched for and visualized with
         TüNDRA (Tübingen Annotated Data Retrieval Application), our in-house web application. Also,
         access to these resources is granted via CLARIN's and Text+'s Federated Content Search. In
         addition to the linguistically annotated corpora, the UniTÜ offers data services in the
         form of vector space word representations and associated software tools. It also offers
         software services for the incremental annotation of external text corpora via the virtual
         research environment WebLicht. Among other things, WebLicht enables the automatic
         enrichment of text corpora with name-entity recognition based on deep learning tools and
         can thus be used as a tool for the automatic enrichment of unstructured data and subsequent
         linking with authority data as well as linked open data. The lexical resources are closely
         linked to other lexical and textual resources and are interoperable with them. The valency
         dictionary of German verbs was derived from large text corpora and is therefore linked to
         corpus data. GermaNet is a lexical database of word meanings for contemporary German nouns,
         verbs and adjectives, which is directly linked to wordnets of more than fifty languages of
         the world via an interlingual index. In addition to other wordnets, GermaNet is linked to
         other digital resources such as Wikipedia and Wiktionary. Taken together, they provide a
         principled basis for assessing lexical similarity and dissimilarity. These two concepts are
         essential for psycho- and neurolinguistic research as well as for topic modeling and
         semantic search in a broad spectrum of disciplines ranging from applications in computer
         science to literary research. Examples include author identification and genre
         classification as well as semantic searches for dictionary data or large metadata
         collections. In addition to the academic sector, GermaNet is also in great demand for
         industrial applications. Furthermore, the linking of word senses via semantic relationships
         provides an ideal starting point for the conversion of wordnet data into linked open data
         formats and for easy integration into knowledge graphs. Accordingly, mapping GermaNet to
         linked open data and knowledge graphs will add significant value to Text+ and provide a
         direct data bridge to other NFDI consortia.</p></info>
   <info xml:lang="de">
      <p>Die Datenressourcen von TALAR (Tübingen Archive for Language Resources) der Universität
         Tübingen umfassen Korpora für gesprochene Sprache und geschriebene Texte, die auf
         verschiedenen Ebenen der linguistischen Annotation von Morphologie, Syntax und Semantik
         annotiert werden. Dazu kommen lexikalischen Ressourcen, die eng verbunden sind mit anderen
         lexikalischen und textuellen Ressourcen aus dem Text+ Konsortium. Die Korpora und
         lexikalischen Ressourcen sind für die datengetriebene Forschung sowohl in der theoretischen
         Linguistik als auch in der Computerlinguistik unverzichtbar. Die Annotationen umfassen
         verschiedene grammatikalische Rahmen und halten sich an die in der Gemeinschaft weit
         verbreiteten Kodierungsstandards sowie an die Kodierungsstandards der International
         Standards Organization (ISO). Diese Ressourcen sind im TALAR-Datenrepository untergebracht,
         das mit dem Core Trust Seal (CTS) zertifiziert wurde und standardisierte Protokolle für den
         Daten-Ingest von externen Datenressourcen entwickelt hat. TALAR beherbergt eine Sammlung
         von weit verbreiteten syntaktisch annotierten Korpora, die so genannten TüBa-Baumbanken für
         Deutsch, Englisch und Japanisch. Darüber hinaus enthält TALAR eine große Anzahl extern
         entwickelter Treebanks im Rahmen der Universal Dependencies. Alle sprachlich annotierten
         Korpora der UniTÜ können mit der Webanwendung TüNDRA (Tübingen Annotated Data Retrieval
         Application) durchsucht und visualisiert werden und sind auch über die CLARIN und Text+
         Federated Content Search zugänglich. Zusätzlich zu den sprachlich annotierten Korpora
         bietet die UniTÜ Datendienste in Form von Vektorraum-Wortdarstellungen und zugehörigen
         Softwaretools an. Darüber hinaus bietet UniTü Softwaredienste für die inkrementelle
         Annotation externer Textkorpora über die virtuelle Forschungsumgebung WebLicht an. WebLicht
         ermöglicht u.a. die automatische Anreicherung von Textkorpora mit einer
         Names-Entity-Erkennung auf der Basis von Deep-Learning-Tools und kann somit als Werkzeug
         für die automatische Anreicherung unstrukturierter Daten und die anschließende Verknüpfung
         mit Autoritätsdaten sowie verknüpften offenen Daten genutzt werden. Die lexikalischen
         Ressourcen sind eng mit anderen lexikalischen und textuellen Ressourcen verbunden und mit
         ihnen interoperabel. Das Valenzwörterbuch der deutschen Verben wurde aus großen Textkorpora
         abgeleitet und ist daher mit Korpusdaten verknüpft. GermaNet ist eine lexikalische
         Datenbank der Wortbedeutungen für zeitgenössiche deutsche Substantive, Verben und
         Adjektive, die über einen interlingualen Index direkt mit Wortnetzen von mehr als fünfzig
         Sprachen der Welt verbunden ist. Neben anderen Wortnetzen ist GermaNet mit anderen digital
         entstandenen Ressourcen wie Wikipedia und Wiktionary verknüpft. Zusammengenommen bieten sie
         eine solide Grundlage für die Beurteilung lexikalischer Ähnlichkeit und Unähnlichkeit.
         Diese beiden Begriffe sind sowohl für die psycho- und neurolinguistische Forschung als auch
         für die Themenmodellierung und die semantische Suche in einem breiten Spektrum von
         Disziplinen, das von Anwendungen in der Informatik bis hin zur literaturwissenschaftlichen
         Forschung reicht, unerlässlich. Hier sind z.B. Autorenidentifizierung und
         Genreklassifizierung sowie die semantische Suche nach Wörterbuchdaten oder nach großen
         Metadatensammlungen zu nennen. Neben dem akademischen Bereich ist GermaNet auch für
         industrielle Anwendungen sehr gefragt. Darüber hinaus bietet die Verknüpfung der Wortsinne
         über semantische Beziehungen einen idealen Ausgangspunkt für die Konvertierung von
         Wortnetzdaten in verknüpfte offene Datenformate und für die einfache Integration in
         Wissensgraphen. Dementsprechend wird das Mapping von GermaNet auf verknüpfte offene Daten
         und Wissensgraphen einen erheblichen Mehrwert für Text+ bieten und eine direkte Datenbrücke
         zu anderen NFDI-Konsortien bilden.</p></info>
   <formats>
      <format id="fMP4">
         <domain>Audiovisual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fWave">
         <domain>Audiovisual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fCMDI">
         <domain>Catalogue Metadata</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fHTML">
         <domain>Documentation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTEI">
         <domain>Documentation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fXML">
         <domain>Documentation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fBMP">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fGIF">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fJPEG">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fPDFA">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fPNG">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fSVG">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTIFF">
         <domain>Image Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fCSV">
         <domain>Lexical Resource</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fSQLite">
         <domain>Lexical Resource</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTSV">
         <domain>Lexical Resource</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fBiBTeX">
         <domain>Metadata</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fR">
         <domain>Statistical Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fSPSS">
         <domain>Statistical Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fSPSS.sav">
         <domain>Statistical Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fSPSS.spv">
         <domain>Statistical Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fCoNLL-U">
         <domain>Text Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fNegra">
         <domain>Text Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTEI">
         <domain>Text Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fXML">
         <domain>Text Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fPDFA">
         <domain>Textual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTCF">
         <domain>Textual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTextPlain">
         <domain>Textual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fCSS">
         <domain>Tool Support</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fGZIP">
         <domain>Packaging</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fRAR">
         <domain>Packaging</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTAR">
         <domain>Packaging</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fXSD">
         <domain>Tool Support</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fXSLT">
         <domain>Tool Support</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fZIP">
         <domain>Packaging</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
   </formats>
</recommendation>