<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schemas/recommendation.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<recommendation xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/recommendation.xsd">
   <header>
      <lastUpdateCommitID>9e38d06072f23a0420a61a20ca6e3f9abd42fc06</lastUpdateCommitID>
      <filter>
         <centreID>HZSK</centreID>
      </filter>
      <respStmt>
         <name>Marcel Fladrich</name>
         <link>https://github.com/mflad</link>
         <reviewDate>2024-07-29</reviewDate>
      </respStmt>
      <centre id="HZSK" deposition="1">
         <centreName>Universität Hamburg, Hamburger Zentrum für Sprachkorpora</centreName>
         <registryLink registry="CLARIN" uri="https://centres.clarin.eu/centre/9"/>
         <registryLink registry="Text+" uri="https://registry.text-plus.org/entity/a5f3e2cc-c2c6-4e26-bdad-63136b626b3a/"/>
         <nodeInfo>
            <ri status="K-Centre">CLARIN</ri>
            <ri status="Collections">Text+</ri>
         </nodeInfo>
      </centre>
    </header>
   <info xml:lang="en">
      <p>The University of Hamburg (UHH), with the expertise of the Hamburg Centre for Language
         Corpora (HZSK) — a collaboration of members from various faculties and institutions of UHH —
         supports the consistency and coordination of computer-assisted empirical research and
         teaching in linguistics, as well as in related disciplines affiliated with the University
         of Hamburg. Together with the HZSK community, UHH aims to ensure the sustainable usability
         of primary linguistic research data beyond the duration of individual research projects.
         The UHH repository, managed by the Center for Sustainable Research Data Management (ZFDM),
         houses more than 50 corpora within the HZSK community. The majority of these corpora belong
         to thematic areas such as multilingual oral and written data, as well as data from less
         commonly spoken or endangered languages.</p>
      <p>See <a href="https://www.slm.uni-hamburg.de/hzsk/angebote/korpora.html">https://www.slm.uni-hamburg.de/hzsk/angebote/korpora.html</a> 
         for more info regarding deposition.</p>
      <p>New data sets (corpora of spoken language) can be added to the 
         <a href="https://www.fdr.uni-hamburg.de/communities/hzsk/?page=1&amp;size=20">HZSK-Community</a> within the
         FDR upon application to Prof. Dr Kristin Bührig, spokesperson of the Hamburg Centre for
         Language Corpora. The prerequisite for the integration of the data into the FDR is that it
         has already been fully curated.</p>
   </info>
   <info xml:lang="de">
      <p>Die Universität Hamburg (UHH) unterstützt mit der Erfahrung des Hamburger Zentrums für
         Sprachkorpora (HZSK), einem Zusammenschluss von Mitgliedern verschiedener Fakultäten und
         Instiutionen der UHH, die Konsistenz und Koordination computergestützter empirischer
         Forschung und Lehre der Sprachwissenschaft sowie der an die UHH angegliederten
         Nachbardisziplinen. Dabei verfolgt sie zusammen mit der Community HZSK das Ziel, die
         nachhaltige Nutzbarkeit sprachwissenschaftlicher Primärforschungsdaten über befristete
         Forschungsprojekte hinaus zu gewährleisten. Das Repositorium der UHH, welches durch das
         Zentrum für nachhaltiges Forschungsdatenmanagement (ZFDM) betrieben wird, beherbergt in der
         HZSK Community mehr als 50 Korpora. Mehrheitlich gehören die Korpora dem thematischen
         Bereich der mehrsprachigen mündlichen und schriftlichen Daten sowie Daten aus weniger
         verbreiteten oder gefährdeten Sprachen an. </p>
      <p>Weitere Informationen finden Sie unter
         <a href="https://www.slm.uni-hamburg.de/hzsk/angebote/korpora.html">https://www.slm.uni-hamburg.de/hzsk/angebote/korpora.html</a>.</p>
      <p>Neue Datensätze (Korpora gesprochener Sprache) können auf Antrag an Prof. Dr. Kristin
         Bührig, Sprecherin des Hamburger Zentrums für Sprachkorpora, in die
         <a href="https://www.fdr.uni-hamburg.de/communities/hzsk/?page=1&amp;size=20">HZSK-Community</a>
         innerhalb des FDRs aufgenommen werden. Voraussetzung für die Integration der Daten ins FDR
         ist ihre bereits vollständige Kuration.</p>
    </info>
   <formats>
      <format id="fEXB">
         <domain>Audiovisual Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fEXS">
         <domain>Audiovisual Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fFLN">
         <domain>Audiovisual Annotation</domain>
         <level>acceptable</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fPraat">
         <domain>Audiovisual Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fTEISpoken">
         <domain>Audiovisual Annotation</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fMPEG-4-AVC">
         <domain>Audiovisual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
         <comment>bit rate up to 5000Kbps, scan type progressive, audio AAC, 48 kHz, 384Kbps, stereo</comment>
      </format>
      <format id="fWave">
         <domain>Audiovisual Source Language Data</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
         <comment>(L)PCM-WAV, 48kHz, 16bit</comment>
      </format>
      <format id="fComa">
         <domain>Contextual Information</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fCMDI">
         <domain>Metadata</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
      </format>
      <format id="fMPEG1">
         <domain>Tool Support</domain>
         <level>recommended</level>
         <comment>MPEG-PS, resolution 352x288, 25 fps, 1000Kbps, constant bit rate, progressive scan type</comment>
      </format>
   </formats>
</recommendation>