<?xml-model href="../../schemas/format.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<format xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="fCSV" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/format.xsd" display="show">
  <titleStmt>
    <title>Comma-Separated Values</title>
    <abbr>CSV</abbr>
  </titleStmt>
  <keyword>database format</keyword>
  <keyword>tabular format</keyword>
  <extId type="LOC">fdd000323</extId>
  <info type="description">
    <p>"CSV is one of the most popular formats for publishing data on the web. It is concise, easy
      to understand by both humans and computers, and aligns nicely to the tabular nature of most
      data. But CSV is also a poor format for data. There is no mechanism within CSV to indicate the
      type of data in a particular column, or whether values in a particular column must be unique.
      It is therefore hard to validate and prone to errors such as missing values or differing data
      types within a column." (from the "CSV on the Web: A Primer")</p>
    <p>Issues to be aware of when submitting CSV-formatted data:</p>
     <ul>
      <li><a href="https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/git-basics/configuring-git-to-handle-line-endings">Line endings must be consistent</a>:
        do not submit files with mixed Windows / Unix endings! (Quick hints: <code>dos2linux</code>,
        <code>linux2dos</code>; adjust save options in your editor; use a HEX editor to spy on the
        endings; see more e.g. at
        <a href="https://blog.cybermindworks.com/post/line-endings-in-code-common-problems-and-how-to-fix-them">Cybermindworks</a>).</li>
        <li>Include column headers</li>
      <li>Watch out for (and preferably weed out) extra columns and extra lines (this is part of the
        general etiquette when submitting data to a centre; there's humans on the other side)</li>
      <li>Contact your target centre to make sure if they have any particular requirements
        concerning CSV, if it is not stated clearly in the SIS.</li>
     </ul>
    <p>See:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/tabular-data-primer/">CSV on the Web: A Primer</a></li>
      <li><a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/tabular-data-model/">Model for Tabular Data and Metadata on the Web</a> (W3C Recommendation; note that this part belongs rather in the Watchtower part of the SIS, but is mentioned here for convenience)</li>
      <li>"<a href="https://www.bitsondisk.com/writing/2021/retire-the-csv/">It's Time to Retire the
          CSV</a>", by Alex Rasmussen (August 16, 2021)</li>
      <li><a href="https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc4180.txt">https://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc4180.txt</a> (informational RFC)</li>
      <li><a href="https://specs.frictionlessdata.io/csv-dialect/">CSV Dialect</a> -- a set of modelling parameters for describing various dialects of CSV</li>
    </ul>
  </info>
  <mimeType>text/csv</mimeType>
  <fileExt>.csv</fileExt>
  <formatFamily>Plain.Delimited</formatFamily>
</format>