<?xml-model href="../../schemas/format.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<format xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="fPressMint"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/format.xsd" display="show">
    <titleStmt>
        <title>Interoperable Corpora of Historical Newspapers</title>
        <abbr>PressMint</abbr>
    </titleStmt>
    <keyword>annotation format</keyword>
    <keyword>TEI</keyword>
    <info type="description">
        <p>PressMint "aims to compile a multilingual, comparable, annotated, translated and
            interoperable set of corpora of European historical newspapers from around the start of
            the 20th century. The PressMint corpora will be openly available, both for download in a
            variety of instances and formats, as well as via several online corpus analysis tools.
            The project will proactively disseminate and foster the use of the corpus
            collection.</p>
        <p>While historical newspapers are of interest to a diverse group of researchers from the
            social sciences and humanities – historians, historical linguists, social scientists,
            ethnologists, anthropologists, media and communication scholars, and cultural studies
            amongst others – contemporary digital resources, tools and methods are still
            underutilised in these fields. Existing corpora are not interoperable, which precludes
            methods for their comparison, as well as any translingual and transnational research, an
            especially important consideration, as statehood and nationhood are highly dynamic in
            Europe in the period to be covered by the project corpora. The PressMint project aims to
            improve this situation by providing a valuable service to the academic community on a
            truly pan-European, multilingual and multidisciplinary level.</p> 
        <p>PressMint includes seventeen national consortia, illustrating the benefit of a
            distributed infrastructure." (from the project homepage)</p>
        <p>See:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://www.clarin.eu/pressmint">Project homepage</a> at clarin.eu</li>
            <li><a href="https://github.com/clarin-eric/PressMint">Technical description and repository</a> at GitHub</li>
            <li><a href="https://clarin-eric.github.io/PressMint/">PressMint schema documentation</a></li>
        </ul>
    </info>
    <mimeType>application/tei+xml</mimeType>
    <fileExt>.xml</fileExt>
    <formatFamily>ParlaMint</formatFamily>
</format>



