<?xml-model href="../../schemas/format.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<format xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="fsrcCode" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/format.xsd" display="show">
  <titleStmt>
    <title>Source code</title>
    <abbr>srcCode</abbr>
  </titleStmt>
  <keyword>software</keyword>
  <keyword>umbrella format</keyword>
    
  <info type="description" umbrella="yes">
    <p>This is a stand-in for when a centre wishes to declare that it accepts certain kinds of
      source code or discourages certain kinds of submissions of this nature. A recommendation using this "umbrella format" <i>must</i>
      be accompanied by a comment.</p>
     
    <p>As is usual with umbrella formats, centres are strongly encouraged to, firstly, check if the programming or query language code 
      they wish to reference is among the <a href="../views/list-formats.xq">formats already described</a> in the SIS or formats 
      that <a href="../views/sanity-check.xq#missing">await getting described</a>. At
      the time when this description is updated, the following kinds of "source code" already have individual descriptions:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fEPS">Encapsulated Postscript</a></li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fPS">Postscript</a></li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fJS">Javascript</a></li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fR">R</a></li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fSQL">Structured Query Language</a></li>
    </ul>

<!-- Note: XSLT is intentionally a dead link; need it for testing of our fallback mechanisms. -->

    <p>A simplifying explicit assumption is that this umbrella (pseudo-)format belongs to the
      "plain-text" family. The practical consequence of that is that formats that constitute source
      code but are based on <a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fXML">XML</a>, such as
      <a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fSVG">Scalable Vector Graphics</a> or
      <a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fXSLT">XSLT</a> need to be classified separately. While
      that can be seen as a semantic impoverishment of the extension of the notion of "source code",
      it is very likely that, on the intuitive plane, the restriction is quite fitting.</p>
    <p>An additional assumption is that there is no clear boundary between programming languages and
      query languages. That is pretty clear when looking from the programming language perspective,
      so it is only a tiny step to add the view from the opposite side and classify SQL as a subtype
      scrCode as well.</p>
  </info>
  <formatFamily>Plain.Statements</formatFamily>
</format>