<?xml-model href="../../schemas/format.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<format xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="fTEI" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/format.xsd" display="show">
  <titleStmt>
    <title>Text Encoding Initiative</title>
    <abbr>TEI</abbr>
  </titleStmt>
  <keyword>umbrella format</keyword>
  <keyword>annotation format</keyword>
  <keyword>format family</keyword>
  <extId type="Wikidata">Q124622467</extId> <!--they do talk about a format, as an extremely general concept-->
  <extDoc type="enWiki">Text Encoding Initiative</extDoc> <!--not really proper for TEI-as-format, but demonstrates the messiness-->
  <info type="description">
    <p>In the context of format recommendations, the unqualified name "TEI" has nearly the same status as 
      "<a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fXML">XML</a>": <i>too general to be meaningful in a recommendation</i>. 
      The best way to view the TEI is not as a format, but rather as a <i>toolkit</i>, composed of (a) the 
      modelling part: <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html">TEI Guidelines</a> 
      and (b) its accompanying <a href="https://tei-c.org/tools/">infrastructure</a>. That toolkit makes it possible 
      (and relatively easy) to create various kinds of XML-based formats with well-defined (human-readable) semantics. 
      No centre wants to claim that they recommend a toolkit as one of the ways to deposit, say, 
      <a href="https://standards.clarin.eu/sis/views/list-domains.xq">Textual Source Language Data</a>, do they?</p>
    <p>It is very practical to assume that, in the context of format recommendations, anything that
      gets labeled "TEI" is formally a
      <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#MD">TEI customisation</a>
      created on the basis of the TEI toolkit -- because <i>there is no single TEI format</i>. And,
      by the gentle and yet unyielding power of the
      <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html">TEI Guidelines</a>, a
      TEI customisation has to meet several conditions. In particular, "a document is TEI-conformant
      if it:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>is a <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFWF">well-formed XML document</a>,</li>
      <li>can be <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFVL">validated against a TEI Schema</a>, that is, a schema derived from the TEI Guidelines,</li>
      <li>conforms to the <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFAM">TEI Abstract Model</a>,</li>
      <li>uses the <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFNS">TEI namespace</a> (and other namespaces where relevant) correctly,</li>
      <li>is documented by means of a <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFOD">TEI-conformant ODD file</a> which refers to the TEI Guidelines." 
        (TEI Guidelines, ch. <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CF">24.4</a>)</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Centres should thus expect that each TEI document submitted to them is either accompanied by the ODD file, 
      or conforms to one of the publicly available ODD specifications
      (either a named TEI out-of-the-box <a href="https://tei-c.org/Guidelines/Customization/">customization</a> or a publicly 
      documented extension), preferably bearing the stamp of a standards body, or encoding established best practices. 
      (Expectations aside, it would seem rather appropriate for centres to supply a comment on what they mean precisely when they say "TEI".)</p>
    <p>An ODD file defines the semantics of a TEI format, by means of prose, datatype restrictions
      and Schematron constraints. It is the basis for creating document grammars (schemas) that the
      conforming TEI document can be validated against. Schemas can be derived e.g. with the help of
      TEI Stylesheets or Roma, XML editor add-ons, etc.</p>
    <p>In the context of CLARIN and LRT applications, the following TEI-based formats are recognizable:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fDTABf">DTABf</a> -- Deutsches Textarchiv Basisformat, used at BBAW</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fI5">I5</a> -- tool format of DeReKo (Deutsches Referenzkorpus), used at IDS Mannheim</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fTEISpoken">ISO/TEI Transcriptions of Spoken Language</a> -- serializing the <a href="../views/view-spec.xq?id=SpecTranScript">corresponding ISO standard</a></li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fLMF">ISO LMF</a> -- TEI serialization of the Lexical Markup Framework (part 4 of the 2020 <a href="../views/view-spec.xq?id=SpecLMF">LMF</a> standard)</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fMenota">Menota</a> -- the Medieval Nordic Text Archive TEI extensions</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fLex0">TEI Lex0</a> -- an OASIS standard for the encoding of (a.o.) retrodigitised dictionaries, maintained by DARIAH</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The above list is not meant to be exhaustive. Please kindly signal to us if you know of a TEI-based format that should be 
      recognised by the SIS and listed above.</p>
    <p>For the purpose of <i>metadata descriptions</i>, free-standing <a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fTEIHeader">TEI headers</a> can often be useful, the more so that they allow "foreign markup" 
      as content of the <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-xenoData.html">xenoData</a> element.</p>
    <p>NOTE: Unqualified TEI used to be treated by the Standards Information System as an umbrella
      format (see the note atop the description file for
      <a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fXML">XML</a> for a brief explanation of the concept of
      umbrella formats). However, it has been decided that it may be more useful in the long run to
      turn unqualified TEI into a pretend-regular format and to provide the extensive explanation of
      its nature that you have just finished reading.</p>
  </info>
  <relation target="SpecTei" type="isDefinedBy"/>
  <mimeType>application/tei+xml</mimeType>
  <fileExt>.tei</fileExt>
  <fileExt>.xml</fileExt>
  <formatFamily>XML</formatFamily>
</format>