<?xml-model href="../../schemas/format.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<format xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="fTEI" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../schemas/format.xsd" display="show">
  <titleStmt>
    <title>Text Encoding Initiative</title>
    <abbr>TEI</abbr>
  </titleStmt>
  <keyword>data format</keyword>
  <keyword>annotation format</keyword>
  <keyword>format family</keyword>
  
  <info type="description">
    <p>In the context of format recommendations, the unqualified name "TEI" has nearly the same status as 
      "<a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fXML">XML</a>": too general to be a meaningful recommendation. 
      The best way to view the TEI is not as a format, but rather as a toolkit (composed out of the 
      modelling part: <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html">TEI Guidelines</a> 
      and its accompanying <a href="https://tei-c.org/tools/">infrastructure</a>) that makes it possible 
      (and relatively easy) to create various kinds of XML-based formats. No centre wants to claim that they
      recommend a toolkit as one of the ways to deposit, say, 
      <a href="https://standards.clarin.eu/sis/views/list-domains.xq">Textual Source Language Data</a>, do they?</p>
    <p>It is very practical to assume that anything that gets labeled "TEI" is formally a 
      <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#MD">customisation</a> of the TEI toolkit. And, by 
      the gentle and yet unyielding power of the 
      <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html">TEI Guidelines</a>, a TEI customisation has 
      to meet several conditions. In particular, "a document is TEI-conformant if it:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>is a <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFWF">well-formed XML document</a>,</li>
      <li>can be <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFVL">validated against a TEI Schema</a>, that is, a schema derived from the TEI Guidelines,</li>
      <li>conforms to the <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFAM">TEI Abstract Model</a>,</li>
      <li>uses the <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFNS">TEI namespace</a> (and other namespaces where relevant) correctly,</li>
      <li>is documented by means of a <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CFOD">TEI-conformant ODD file</a> which refers to the TEI Guidelines." 
        (TEI Guidelines, ch. <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/USE.html#CF">24.4</a>)</li>
    </ul>
    <p>By rule of thumb, centres should expect that each TEI document submitted to them is either
      accompanied by the ODD file, or conforms to one of the publicly available ODD specifications
      (either a named TEI out-of-the-box customization or a publicly documented extension),
      preferably bearing the stamp of a standards body, or encoding established best practices.</p>
    <p>An ODD file defines the semantics of a TEI format, by means of prose, datatype restrictions
      and Schematron constraints. It is the basis for creating document grammars (schemas) that the
      conforming TEI document can be validated against. Schemas can be derived e.g. with the help of
      TEI Stylesheets or Roma, XML editor add-ons, etc.</p>
    <p>In the context of CLARIN and LRT applications, the following TEI-based formats are recognizable:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fDTABf">DTABf</a> -- Deutsches Textarchiv Basisformat, used at BBAW</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fI5">I5</a> -- tool format of DeReKo (Deutsches Referenzkorpus), used at IDS Mannheim</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fTEISpoken">ISO/TEI Transcriptions of Spoken Language</a> -- serializing the <a href="../views/view-spec.xq?id=SpecTranScript">corresponding ISO standard</a></li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fLMF">ISO LMF</a> -- TEI serialization of the Lexical Markup Framework (part 4 of the 2020 <a href="../views/view-spec.xq?id=SpecLMF">LMF</a> standard)</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fMenota">Menota</a> -- the Medieval Nordic Text Archive TEI extensions</li>
      <li><a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fLex0">TEI Lex0</a> -- an OASIS standard for the encoding of (a.o.) retrodigitised dictionaries, maintained by DARIAH</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The above list is not meant to be exhaustive. While the above items would generally qualify
      as TEI extensions, the
      <a href="https://tei-c.org/Guidelines/Customization/">environment of the TEI Guidelines</a>
      defines a series of restrictions on the overall TEI schema, referred to as 'templates' and
      meant as bases for further customization, as well as three fully-defined and maintained
      customizations: TEI Lite, TEI simplePrint, TEI Tite.</p>
    <p>For the purpose of metadata descriptions, free-standing <a href="../views/view-format.xq?id=fTEIHeader">TEI headers</a> can often be useful, the more so that they allow "foreign markup" 
      as content of the <a href="https://tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/ref-xenoData.html">xenoData</a> element.</p>
  </info>
  <relation target="SpecTei" type="isDefinedBy"/>
  <mimeType>application/tei+xml</mimeType>
  <fileExt>.tei</fileExt>
  <fileExt>.xml</fileExt>
  <formatFamily>XML</formatFamily>
</format>